<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="0.92" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>The New Yorker</title>
<link>http://www.newyorker.com</link>
<description>Online version of the weekly magazine, with current articles, cartoons, blogs, audio, video, slide shows, an archive of articles and abstracts back to 1925.</description>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 22:04:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<docs>http://backend.userland.com/rss092</docs>
<language>en-US</language>
<!-- generator="WordPress/4.0.8" -->
<item>
<title>Jeb and Hillary: A Tale of Two Front-Runners</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p class=\"descender\"><p>The contrast couldn’t have been more stark. On Friday, as Hillary Clinton was basking in the&nbsp;reaction to her marathon appearance before the House Select Committee on Benghazi, her communications director, Jennifer Palmieri, <a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2015/10/hillary-clinton-campaign-benefits-benghazi-hearing-215107">told reporters</a> that the hour between nine and ten o’clock on Thursday night, after the hearing finally finished, was the&nbsp;campaign’s best fund-raising hour yet. And also on Friday, A.F.S.C.M.E., the largest public-sector union in the country, <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2015/10/23/politics/afscme-hillary-clinton-endorsement/">announced</a> that it was&nbsp;endorsing Clinton for the Presidency—an important win in her tussle with Senator Bernie Sanders for the backing of organized labor.</p>
 <p>Meanwhile, the campaign of the supposed Republican front-runner, Jeb Bush, was letting it be known that it was <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/politics/articles/2015-10-23/jeb-bush-orders-across-the-board-pay-cuts-for-struggling-campaign">laying off people</a> and slashing its payroll by forty per cent. It’s well known that the Bush campaign has been spending heavily, and there have been persistent rumors that, with the candidate trailing badly in the polls, its fund-raising efforts had stalled. Evidently, these rumors were accurate.&nbsp;Seeking to put a positive spin on things, the Bush campaign portrayed the cost-cutting as an effort to play the long game and direct resources toward the early primary states—Iowa, New Hampshire, South Carolina. “This is about winning the race,” a Bush adviser&nbsp;told Bloomberg Politics. “We’re doing it now and making the shifts with confidence. We expect to win.”</p>
 <p>Campaign advisers have to make such statements. But many people in the G.O.P. are losing confidence in Bush. A <a href="http://www.quinnipiac.edu/images/polling/ia/ia10222015_igv72sh.pdf">new poll from Iowa</a>, which was released on Thursday, showed the former Florida governor garnering just five per cent of the votes among likely Republican voters. Perhaps&nbsp;the poll, from Quinnipiac University, was an outlier? No, it wasn’t. On Friday,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/politics/articles/2015-10-23/carson-surges-past-trump-in-latest-bloomberg-politics-des-moines-register-iowa-poll">another Iowa survey</a>, this one carried out by the Des Moines <em>Register</em> and Bloomberg Politics, also showed Bush at just five per cent.&nbsp;“By any honest analysis, the first ten months of this year have been a political disaster,” a senior Republican told the <em><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/politics/first-draft/2015/10/23/trailing-in-polls-jeb-bush-cuts-staff-and-salaries-vowing-focus-on-early-states/">Times</a></em>, adding that it was “an unbelievable position to be twisted into, from ‘shock and awe’ to ‘aw, shucks.’&nbsp;”</p>
 <p>Why is the Republican pre-race favorite doing so much worse than the Democratic favorite?</p>
 <p>The obvious answer is that Bush has had Donald Trump to deal with, and Clinton hasn’t. In virtually monopolizing media coverage and subjecting Bush to months of public criticism, the New York billionaire has transformed the dynamics of the G.O.P. race in a way that almost nobody anticipated—a point the managers of the Bush campaign acknowledged in an internal memo announcing the cost cuts. “We would be less than forthcoming if we said we predicted in June that a reality television star supporting Canadian-style single-payer health care and partial-birth abortion would be leading the G.O.P. primary,” the memo said.</p>
 <p>With Bush’s campaign having been outpaced in such outrageous fashion, it is hard not to feel a little sympathy for him. However, his&nbsp;problems can’t be entirely attributed to the Donald.&nbsp;According to the <a href="http://www.realclearpolitics.com/epolls/2016/president/us/2016_republican_presidential_nomination-3823.html">Real Clear Politics poll average</a>,&nbsp;he’s also&nbsp;running behind Ben Carson, Marco Rubio, and Ted Cruz, and nationwide he has the support of just 7.2 per cent of likely Republican voters. For a candidate whose main selling point was supposed to be his electability, these are terrible numbers. On the Democratic side, Clinton, even at the height of concerns about her e-mail server, maintained a healthy lead in the national polls.</p>
 <p>In part, Bush’s weak numbers reflect the fact he has run a weak campaign—one dogged by his tendency to mangle the English language, or, at least, to use it carelessly. In his first big speech, back in February, he <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2015/02/18/politics/jeb-bush-iraq-speech/">confused Iran with Iraq</a> and got mixed up about how many fighters the Islamic State has. Since then, the list of phrases he has been forced to clarify or disavow is long and embarrassing:&nbsp;“People need to&nbsp;<a href="http://thehill.com/blogs/ballot-box/gop-primaries/247317-jeb-bush-people-need-to-work-longer-hours">work longer hours</a>”; “<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/plum-line/wp/2015/08/05/what-jeb-bushs-gaffe-on-womens-health-really-tells-us/">I’m not sure we need half a billion dollars&nbsp;on women’s health-care issues</a>”;&nbsp;“<a href="http://time.com/4008888/jeb-bush-anchor-baby-asians/">anchor babies</a>”; “<a href="http://abcnews.go.com/US/jeb-bush-stuff-response-gun-violence/story?id=34209380">stuff happens</a>.” On the basis of what we’ve seen so far, it’s hard to avoid the conclusion that Bush simply isn’t a good communicator. Indeed, he often appears to be a terrible one.&nbsp;Asked on Saturday whether his campaign’s cost-cutting showed it was in crisis, he <a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/elections/2016/2015/10/24/jeb-bush-campaign-tim-scott-trey-gowdy-charleston/74525090/">said</a>, “Blah, blah, blah. That’s my answer:&nbsp;blah, blah, blah.”</p>
 <p>If Bush were wowing the world with innovative and substantive policy proposals, his verbal shortcomings could perhaps be overlooked. But he isn’t. His tax-cutting economic plan, which he claims will increase G.D.P. growth to four per cent a year, is largely based on <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/john-cassidy/jeb-bush-and-the-return-of-voodoo-economics">wishful thinking</a>.&nbsp;His foreign-policy speeches are so vague that they’re hard to evaluate. On social issues, such as guns and abortion, he has said little to distinguish himself from the G.O.P. pack.&nbsp;In 2000, his brother George ran on the platform of “compassionate Conservatism,” which was his way of distinguishing himself from Newt Gingrich and other Republican bomb throwers. Jeb’s only memorable slogan is “Jeb!”</p>
 <p>Clinton, on the other hand, has made it clear that she is running as a progressive candidate; in the first Democratic debate, she defined herself as “a progressive who believes in getting things done.” To back up this talk, she has rolled out a series of proposals, including paid sick leave, expanded childcare for pre-schoolers, a higher minimum wage, tax breaks for firms that promote employee share ownership, and a series of measures designed to make college more affordable. None of the things she has proposed is particularly radical, but taken together, they amount to a concerted effort to tackle wage stagnation and boost the middle class.</p>
 <p>Bush has nothing comparable to offer. And even if he improved as a communicator and Trump dropped out of the race, there would be no assurance that he would win the nomination. Indeed, it now appears possible that his entire campaign is based on two false premises.</p>
 <p>The first is that Republican voters want a&nbsp;shift to the center.&nbsp;The one area where Bush has issued a proposal that separates him from other Republican candidates is immigration. To his credit, he has stuck to the position that law-abiding undocumented immigrants should be given the opportunity to obtain U.S. citizenship. About all that has done is win him the enmity of conservative pundits and talk-show hosts, who accuse him of promoting an “amnesty.” And on this issue, most Republican voters agree with Rush Limbaugh and Sean Hannity. Polls consistently show that a majority of them&nbsp;<a href="http://www.washingtonexaminer.com/poll-republican-voters-favor-deporting-illegal-immigrants/article/2569031">favor the mass deportation</a>&nbsp;of undocumented aliens—an issue Trump has&nbsp;<a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2015/09/poll-gop-donald-trump-2016-iowa-213249">built his candidacy on</a>.</p>
 <p>The second shaky premise is the notion that Republicans are keen on restoring the Bush dynasty. From the beginning, this seemed like a dubious proposition: never in its history has America had three Presidents from the same family. When Jeb entered the race, G.O.P. supporters were being asked to embrace the possibility of three Bush Presidents in thirty years.</p>
 <p>In its eagerness to promote someone whom it considered electable, the G.O.P. establishment sought to play down the dynastic aspect of Bush’s candidacy, portraying Jeb as very different from his elder brother: more thoughtful, more conservative, more articulate. Despite these efforts, no groundswell of support emerged for a Bush restoration. Indeed, it now appears that Barbara Bush, Jeb’s mother, spoke for many Republicans when she <a href="http://thecaucus.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/04/25/barbara-bush-on-son-jeb-in-2016-weve-had-enough-bushes/">said</a>, in April, 2013, “There are other people out there that are very qualified, and&nbsp;we’ve had enough Bushes.”</p>
 <p>The Clinton campaign raises dynastic issues of its own, but there are important differences. As evidenced by the Adams, the Harrisons, and the Roosevelts, the idea of having two Presidents from the same family isn’t alien to the American tradition <span style="font-family: adobe-caslon-pro,Times,Georgia,serif;">(even though the Roosevelts were only fifth cousins)</span>. And, in serving as a U.S. Senator and as Secretary of State, Hillary Clinton has established credentials independent of her husband’s time in office. At the same time, it’s also important to note that Bill Clinton’s Presidency is far more popular among Democrats than George W. Bush’s Presidency is among Republicans. Some left-leaning Democrats may regard Bill Clinton’s Administration as a neo-liberal sellout, but most associate it with peace, prosperity, and the ability to outlast Republican attacks.</p>
 <p>Even among Republicans, the last Bush Presidency inspires few fond feelings. It ended with the economy in recession, and with the U.S. military trapped in two costly and unwinnable-seeming wars. For a time, Jeb and his establishment backers pretended they could sustain a 2016 campaign that ignored this toxic legacy, but once Trump entered the race, the strategy proved unsustainable. In portraying the Iraq war as a disaster and repeatedly tying Jeb to his elder brother, Trump forced Republicans to confront the question of why anybody would think that putting another Bush in the White House was a good idea.</p>
 <p>There are still more than three months to go before the G.O.P. Iowa caucus, but if Bush is going to re-emerge as the front-runner, he’ll have to do a much better job of answering Trump’s charges. He’ll get his first opportunity this week, at the Republican debate in Boulder, Colorado. When the pressure was on this past week, at the first Democratic debate and then at the Benghazi hearing, Clinton rose to the occasion and gave her campaign a huge boost. Now, it’s Bush’s turn. “Jeb really needs a knockout performance—it needs to be all him with nobody even close,” a New Hampshire Republican&nbsp;<a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2015/10/insiders-trump-nomination-looking-more-likely-215087#ixzz3pWJ6Yb74">told Politico</a>. “Otherwise those fumes he’s on are going to evaporate even quicker.”</p>
]]>
</description>
<link>http://www.newyorker.com/news/john-cassidy/jeb-and-hillary-a-tale-of-two-frontrunners</link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Holly Andres’s Adolescent Fairy Tales</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p>Holly Andres’s photo series seem to unfold in the darkened corners of a fairy-tale dream space—a place where the private lives of girls intersect with the mysteries, and occasional dangers, of the real world. The stories she tells—in lush, cinematic scope, like movies made up of only still images—are often drawn from stories in her own childhood: the adventures of a group of adolescent girls hungry for new experience; the trauma of two young sisters who venture too close to a hornet&#8217;s nest. Her latest series, “The Fallen Fawn,” which will go on display at the Robert Mann Gallery on October 29th, tells the story of two sisters who discover a woman’s abandoned suitcase by a river behind their house. Treating it as a valuable treasure, they bring it home, hide it underneath the bed, and secretly dress up in the &#8220;mystery woman&#8217;s&#8221; belongings at night. In this story, as in her other work, the young protagonists project both the plucky curiosity of Nancy Drew and the fragile innocence of a sleeping Snow White.</p>]]>
</description>
<link>http://www.newyorker.com/culture/photo-booth/holly-andress-adolescent-fairy-tales</link>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Propaganda Precursor to “The Act of Killing”</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p class=\"descender\"><p>On the evening of September 30th, hundreds of men from the Islamic Defenders Front, an Indonesian hard-line Muslim group, streamed into a large square in east Jakarta. They had come to commemorate the fiftieth anniversary of the murder of six anti-Communist Indonesian generals by left-wing conspirators, including members of the Indonesian Communist Party (Partai Komunis Indonesia or P.K.I.).&nbsp;<a href="http://www.insideindonesia.org/dictionary-of-a-disaster">Fifty years ago</a>, Suharto, one of the few surviving major generals, responded by assuming control of the military and routing the poorly organized left-wing plotters. He portrayed their plot as an attempted coup and used it as a justification for rounding up and murdering hundreds of thousands of alleged Communists throughout Indonesia. Today, Indonesia’s state officials continue to support the Suharto line: that the generals’ murders represented a full-blown coup attempt and that the 1965 killings prevented an otherwise imminent Communist takeover. Fifty years after the event that set the mass murder in motion, the men in the courtyard had come to watch a film about the slaughter.</p>
 <p>There were a few speeches before the film began. The Jakarta police chief, Inspector General Tito Karnavian, denounced Communism and paid homage to the slain generals. “Islam and Communism cannot exist together,” Karnavian said, arguing that Indonesians should remain vigilant against any ideology that threatens Islam. Habib Rizieq, the fiery head of the Islamic Defenders Front, also denounced the long-defunct P.K.I. Rizieq said that his family had been among those that were threatened by the P.K.I. He denounced attempts to rehabilitate the Party, which he said would only lead to Communism’s reëmergence. “The police and military must watch out to insure that the P.K.I. doesn’t rise again!” he said.</p>
 <p>Finally, Rizieq pivoted to his major point. “Why don’t we know our own history?” he asked. “Because after&nbsp;<em>Reformasi</em>”<em>—</em>the transition to democracy that followed Suharto’s reign—“we were too afraid to show&nbsp;‘Pengkhianatan G30s/PKI.’ ”</p>
 <p>Until 1984, Suharto’s regime did not release any films that directly addressed the events of 1965. The best explanation for this, according to Krishna Sen, the dean of Indonesian Studies at the University of Western Australia, is that Indonesia’s wounds were simply too raw. She recounted a conversation she had with Rear Marshal Budiardjo, Suharto’s minister of information from 1968 to 1973, about the government’s decision not to release a 1968 film that a Suharto loyalist had made about the Army’s triumph over the P.K.I. “Why would we advertise a civil war?” he said to her.</p>
 <p>But in 1984 Suharto’s New Order regime, which was beginning to face popular resistance, changed tack. The government funded a major film production about the killings, guided by the accomplished Indonesian director Arifin C. Noer, with the working title “A History of the New Order.” The resulting film, the docudrama&nbsp;“Pengkhianatan G30s/PKI<em>”</em>&nbsp;(“Treachery of the September 30th Movement/PKI”), is in part a “Reefer Madness”-style horror flick depicting gruesome Communist atrocities, many of which never occurred. In perhaps the film’s most famous scene, three of the captured anti-Communist generals are brutally&nbsp;<a href="http://m.dev.tempo.co/read/news/2015/09/30/078705271/Benarkah-Ada-Penyiksaan-Jenderal-Korban-G30S-1965">tortured</a>—their eyes are gouged out, lighted cigarettes are put out on their skin, they are repeatedly whipped and stabbed—while Communist women perform a macabre dance ritual to celebrate their death. (In fact, according to one of Suharto’s surviving medical examiners, who inspected the generals’ bodies, there were no signs that they had been tortured before they were shot.) Even more telling than the film’s exaggerations are its elisions: it concludes with the recovery of the slain generals’ bodies, and shows a dashing Suharto defeating Communists and restoring order to the country, but does not depict the military’s extermination of hundreds of thousands of alleged P.K.I. supporters.</p>
 <p>The Suharto regime considered the film such an effective exercise in propaganda that it mandated annual showings in schools and on TVRI, the state television channel, from shortly after the film’s release, in 1984, until the regime’s collapse, in 1998. A poll conducted in 2000 by&nbsp;<em>Tempo</em>, Indonesia’s investigative weekly, found that ninety-seven per cent of Indonesian secondary-school students had seen the film at least once, with eighty-seven per cent of those who had watched the film reporting that they had seen it multiple times.</p>
 <p>Given the rising disaffection with Suharto’s regime during those years, it might not have been as effective a propaganda tool as he had intended. “I don’t know if propaganda succeeds in a situation where people are already disenchanted,” Sen said. Still, the graphic violence of the film shocked Indonesian students into believing that Communists were evil. Dian Agustino, a thirty-four-year-old communications consultant, vividly remembers a reënactment of the murder of Adi Irma, the daughter of an anti-Communist general. “We were so sympathetic to her because she was just a small child, who was killed even though she hadn’t sinned,” Agustino said. The film found its way into childhood games and rivalries, she added. “The most awful kid at school, we’d refer to as P.K.I., or if I was mean to you, you’d call me P.K.I.,” she said.</p>
 <p>In 1998, the Asian financial crisis sent the value of the Indonesia rupiah plunging. Sky-high inflation, combined with revelations about the corruption of Suharto’s inner circle, caused large protests throughout the country. Finally, the military withdrew its backing of Suharto, whose thirty-two-year rule came to an end.&nbsp;<em>Reformasi</em>&nbsp;followed, ushering in Indonesia’s democratic system. Bans on the press were lifted, and magazines that had been shuttered by Suharto quickly returned. September 30th, 1998, marked the first anniversary of the generals’ killings that&nbsp;“G30s/PKI<em>”</em><em>&nbsp;</em>was not broadcast on TVRI, or widely shown in schools.</p>
 <p>The liberalization of media meant that Indonesians could, for the first time, openly discuss different accounts of the events of 1965. Angelina Anggraeni, a thirty-three-year-old architect, who grew up learning Indonesian history from the film&nbsp;“G30s/PKI”<em>&nbsp;</em>as well as from Suharto’s textbooks, finally began reading deeply about the killings. “After 1998, I realized, Oh, that was all brainwashing,” Anggraeni said.</p>
 <p>It was not until 2012 that another prominent Indonesian-language film dealt directly with the 1965 killings. It came from an unlikely source. Joshua Oppenheimer, an American filmmaker, had been sent to Indonesia by an international union in the early 2000s to give filmmaking tutorials to plantation workers in North Sumatra. The workers, many of whom were dying from diseases caused by exposure to pesticides, wanted to make a film about their efforts to form a union. But the Belgian company that owned the plantation hired a local paramilitary group, the Pancasila Youth, to terrorize the workers, and they gave up on the union. Some of them explained to Oppenheimer that the Pancasila Youth had killed their parents and grandparents for being a part of a union, in 1965. “It wasn’t just the poison that was killing the workers, it was fear,” Oppenheimer remembers thinking.</p>
 <p>In 2003, Oppenheimer began interviewing survivors of the 1965 killings, but the Army got word and compelled survivors to stop participating. Still, the survivors implored Oppenheimer to make the film regardless, and they offered him an odd suggestion: perhaps he could speak with the perpetrators, who were often vocal about their involvement. And so members of the Pancasila Youth became the protagonists of Oppenheimer’s first film about the slaughter,&nbsp;“The Act of Killing,”<em>&nbsp;</em>in which Oppenheimer shows members of North Sumatra’s Pancasila Youth making a film about slaughtering leftists in 1965. On-screen, Paramilitary members brag about the murders they perpetrated, but also, at different moments, make blunt admissions about the guilt that haunts them. Oppenheimer’s next film,&nbsp;“The Look of Silence,” switches focus by exploring the way that violence has affected the relatives of the victims. The film follows Adi, a middle-aged optometrist, as he seeks the true story about his older brother’s murder by anti-Communist paramilitaries. The juxtaposition of Adi’s family’s fear and grief with ex-paramilitary members’ cheerful memories of torturing his brother and dumping the corpse into a river captures both the horror of the 1965 mass murder and the ways in which modern Indonesia has so far failed to reckon with it.</p>
 <p>Oppenheimer’s documentaries flip the script on&nbsp;“G30s/PKI”&nbsp;by recording aging Indonesian death-squad leaders discussing the atrocities they committed against alleged Communists: decapitating them, drinking their blood, tossing their corpses into the river. Oppenheimer explained the contrast between his film and&nbsp;“G30s/PKI,” saying, “If&nbsp;‘G30s/PKI<em>’</em><em>&nbsp;</em>is both the lie and the threat about what happens if you depart from the lie, then my film is the child in ‘The Emperor’s New Clothes’ who says, ‘This is all a lie and you know it.’ ”</p>
 <p>Oppenheimer says that his films consciously counter&nbsp;“G30s/PKI<em>”</em><em>&nbsp;</em>because Suharto’s film became the “symbolic metonym” that Indonesians used to understand the tragedy. “If we wanted to deconstruct it as a lie, we had to engage with its symbolic language,” he said. Anwar Congo<em>,</em><em>&nbsp;</em>the paramilitary leader whose guilt is explored in&nbsp;“The Act of Killing,”&nbsp;says in the film, “For me, [‘G30s/PKI’] is the one thing that makes me feel not guilty. I watch the film and feel reassured.”<em>&nbsp;</em>In fact, “G30s/PKI” played such a large role in the former paramilitary leaders’ understanding of their own actions that when, in&nbsp;“The Act of Killing,” these leaders make a film about their role in suppressing Communists during 1965, they incorporate elements of the 1984 film. In one of the more surreal parts of the film, Congo creates a nightmare set piece in which relatives of the people he killed seek vengeance against him. This scene incorporates lines from “G30s/PKI”<em>&nbsp;</em>wholesale (the avenger screams, “You’d better listen to me, or my sickle will do the talking! My sickle is rusty! Now your eye will enjoy the rust!”), and makeup artists use stills from “G30s/PKI” as guidance for how to make the actors’ faces look bloody. “It felt perfect they should remake shots from ‘G30s/PKI<em>’</em><em>&nbsp;</em> in order to show that their own nightmares are influenced by their propaganda,” Oppenheimer told me.</p>
 <p>When Oppenheimer released&nbsp;“The Act of Killing,”<em>&nbsp;</em>he hoped that the Indonesian people&nbsp;would quickly acknowledge the scale of the crimes committed against P.K.I. supporters. “In effect, the films didn’t have much work to do. Everyone knew the king was naked but couldn’t say. Everyone knew the propaganda was a lie but couldn’t say that. I thought once we intervened in that cognitive dissonance that would be it.”</p>
 <p>Oppenheimer and his team never released&nbsp;“The Act of Killing”&nbsp;or&nbsp;“The Look of Silence”<em>&nbsp;</em>in Indonesian theatres, in order to avoid facing a ban by Indonesia’s national Film Censorship Institute. Nonetheless, in response to Indonesian conservatives’ angry reaction to public showings of&nbsp;“The Look of Silence,”<em>&nbsp;</em>the Institute placed a ban on commercial showings of the film. Throughout the country, private showings have been&nbsp;<a href="http://nasional.tempo.co/read/news/2014/12/17/078629227/polisi-bubarkan-diskusi-film-senyap-di-aji-yogya">shut down</a>&nbsp;by police and violently&nbsp;<a href="http://jakartaglobe.beritasatu.com/news/hard-line-islamic-group-storms-ugm-student-screening-senyap/">disrupted</a>&nbsp;by Islamist and anti-Communist militant groups, who have interpreted the Film Censorship Institute’s policy as a blanket ban on all public screenings of the film. On September 30th, one of the biggest planned screenings of&nbsp;“The Look of Silence,” at the Jakarta Theological Seminary, was cancelled by police. (Oppenheimer counted sixty-two planned screenings throughout the country, the majority of which did not get shut down.)</p>
 <p>I spoke with Muhammad Fuad, the lead commando in efforts by an activist group called the People’s Islamic Forum to disrupt showings of&nbsp;“The Look of Silence”<em>&nbsp;</em>in Yogyakarta. Fuad is a Muslim hard-liner, but, like many conservative Indonesians who want to move on from Suharto-era propaganda, he did not endorse&nbsp;“G30s/PKI.” “We must remind people of the true history, but not through that movie. Better that we do it through dialogue and the historical evidence that exists.” He went on, “We don’t know whether the film is one hundred per cent true or not.” Nonetheless, he thought that Oppenheimer’s films were much more problematic. He said that it was because of his organization’s commitment to preventing the return of Communism that he had been asked to disrupt dozens of showings of&nbsp;“The Look of Silence.<em>”</em><em>&nbsp;</em>“My colleagues that have expertise on the matter have looked into it and concluded that the film is consistent with Communist teachings,” Fuad said.</p>
 <p>A year ago, when the reformist President Joko “Jokowi” Widodo took office, activists had high hopes that the fiftieth anniversary of the killings would bring a serious attempt to redress past wrongs. But even Jokowi’s most milquetoast statements about reconciliation have met harsh resistance from conservative politicians and Islamist groups, who paint the P.K.I. as a symbol of the secular and progressive forces that they believe continue to undermine Indonesia. During the days leading up to the October 1st commemoration, several of Jokowi’s confidants attempted to stave off controversy by announcing that the President had no intention of apologizing to the victims of the anti-Communist slaughter. So it was no surprise when, at a ceremony commemorating the slain generals, Jokowi made clear that he, like Indonesia’s previous President, Susilo Bambang Yudhoyono, would not be offering an official apology. “<a href="http://www.rappler.com/indonesia/107717-jokowi-tidak-minta-maaf-pki-tragedi-1965">Apologize</a>&nbsp;to whom?” he asked. “Who should forgive whom when both sides claim to be victims?”</p>
]]>
</description>
<link>http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/the-propaganda-precursor-to-the-act-of-killing</link>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Too-Easy History of “Suffragette”</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p class=\"descender\"><p>You’d have to be a moral idiot to oppose a woman’s right to vote. And yet many of the people in Great Britain who opposed that right a hundred or so years ago were not, at the time, considered moral idiots—some of them have even gone down in history as esteemed, for other, unrelated activities. Among those opponents there were women, for a large set of complicated reasons. But you would not know any of this from watching “Suffragette,” directed by Sarah Gavron, written by Abi Morgan.</p>
 <p>Of course, that’s not what the movie’s “about,” as if about-ness were a form of artistic predestination that absolves filmmakers of decisions about what to put into a movie. What “Suffragette” is in fact about is so substantial, so serious, and, at times, so surprising, that the movie’s lack of vision (both literal and metaphorical), its failures of imagination, its built-in inhibitions and shortcuts, are all the more unfortunate. They keep a decent and worthy, amiable and unchallenging film short of the greatness of the subject itself.</p>
 <p>The movie is set in London, in 1912. Its protagonist, Maud Watts (Carey Mulligan), is a twenty-four-year-old woman who works in a large commercial laundry, as she has done since the age of seven. Married to Sonny (Ben Whishaw), mother to young George (Adam Michael Dodd), she’s utterly disengaged from politics until she chances to see a suffragette throw a brick through a shop window in protest. She herself gets caught up in the resulting turmoil, and that experience—together with a suddenly sharpened revulsion at the subjugation (including sexual) that she and other women endure at the laundry—leads her to accompany a suffragette colleague, Violet Miller (Anne-Marie Duff), to a parliamentary hearing, where, under the force of circumstances, she testifies about women’s working conditions at the laundry and makes clear that the cause of women’s votes is inseparable from her hope for reform overall.</p>
 <p>As Maud becomes increasingly involved in the movement for women’s suffrage, she also manages to get arrested; when she returns home from a week in jail, Sonny—who has become the butt of jokes at work and is exhorted to “control” her—urges her to give up her activities and attend to their home life. It’s ultimately the irreparable deterioration of her home life (which includes a narrative gut-punch that’s thrown with the full force of injustice) that leads Maud to fling herself into political action with abandon and fury.</p>
 <p>The nodal point of the movie, its crucial inspiration, is the domestic subjugation of women, by law, to their husbands. In one telling scene, the police inspector named Steed (Brendan Gleeson), who heads the surveillance and infiltration of the suffrage movement, oversees the arrest of a group of women and orders them not jailed but returned to their homes, saying, “Let their husbands deal with them.” In “Suffragette,” the threat of domestic violence hangs over the heads of British women. Their lack of voting rights is matched by their lack of civil rights overall—including the right to dispose of their property as they see fit, and even the right, as a mother, to exercise authority in relation to children. What’s more, women’s domestic subjugation to husbands is matched in public life by the menace of sexual abuse at work, inflicted with impunity by male supervisors. The depiction of this horrific circle—a legal system that refuses to grant women basic rights and allows them no power to change that system, keeping them in a double state of subjugation, to the public and domestic authority of men—is the infuriating vortex that lends the movie an inspirational energy even though its aesthetic inspiration is minor and its approach to history is simplistic.</p>
 <p>The narrow focus on Maud’s own activities and decisions sacrifices a view of the wider world in which she decides and acts—even from the calculated limits of her own perspective. Since the women’s suffrage movement included only a small minority of women, how in fact did they seem to Maud and to her colleagues? The movie unfortunately perpetuates a repellent cinematic myth: that of the stoically silent working class. Poor people who lack formal education don’t actually do less talking than wealthy and educated people, yet the inarticulateness of working people, their inability to speak even to each other, is a facile trope of movies—especially movies in recent decades made by university graduates about working people.</p>
 <p>It’s of more than historical interest to know what Maud and her colleagues thought—just as it’s a matter of more than idle curiosity what the arguments of the day, made in Parliament or in the press or in a laundry or in a factory, against votes for women would have been. For instance, it’s odd that the movie never makes clear the fact that, at the time in which the movie is set,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.archive.org/stream/representationof00frasrich/representationof00frasrich_djvu.txt" target="_blank">many&nbsp;<em>male</em>&nbsp;British subjects</a>&nbsp;lacked the right to vote (which depended on property ownership).</p>
 <p>I couldn’t help wondering about trade unions—whether laundry workers were protected by unions, whether employees in other businesses had union representation, whether the unions took a stand on suffrage. For that matter, what about the suffrage movement itself? Were its class distinctions utterly nonexistent, or so thin as to be instantly and effortlessly overcome? For all the police repression of its activities, the movement is housed in a sturdy building emblazoned with its name and purpose. Was there a branch that was tolerated alongside the one that was repressed? What made the difference? The view of the movement in “Suffragette” is monolithic, with differences appearing only on the matter of tactics—of the tendency toward violence (directed solely against property, not against people)—and even these are mentioned only briefly, with little discussion of practicalities. For all its apparent political history, “Suffragette” shies away from politics.</p>
 <p>That’s where the movie’s lack of directorial style converges with the thinness of its substance. I found myself thinking about Terence Davies, whose movies about English life in the nineteen-fifties don’t stint on its injustices, but also capture the distinctive flavors and intimate joys, even, of families facing hardships, and of individuals whose very identity was the subject of fear and repression. Seeing the possibility of beauty in troubled times is more than a matter of Davies’ own artistry; it’s the difference between a work of art that respects the complexity of historical experience and a sentimentalized reduction of it.</p>
 <p>Watching “Suffragette,” I sensed that the onesidedness of its argument was rooted in a different sort of fear—that of giving aid and comfort to the enemy, of passing ammunition across the lines of ongoing battles. It’s as if the very notion of a debate, implicit or explicit—even one in which reason is entirely on the side of the movie’s heroines—suggests that there’s another side to the conflict that’s even worthy of mention. It’s easy—too easy—for a movie about history to present the great changes of the past as the triumph of reason over unreason, without indicating the profound investment in tradition and continuity, and the fear of change, that even the beneficiaries of that change might feel. And this very fear of giving aid to defenders of injustice today has an aesthetic correlate—namely, a resistance to beauty: as if the free-spirited artistry that can find pleasure even in times and places of trouble were legitimizing the source of that trouble. That’s why “Suffragette,” like many contemporary movies on the subject of the advancement of just causes, is a comfort to its viewers, but not a tool; a gratification, but not a stimulus. It takes no risks and offers no challenge.</p>
]]>
</description>
<link>http://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/the-too-easy-history-of-suffragette</link>
</item>
<item>
<title>An Attack and an Identity Crisis in Sweden</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p class=\"descender\"><p>“We took shelter under the tables. Everyone was scared. We cried,” a shaken eleven-year-old girl <a href="http://www.aftonbladet.se/nyheter/article21630464.ab" target="_blank">told reporters</a>, as she described how she and her classmates hid from a masked attacker who killed two and injured several others at a school on Thursday. Her tale of the hours in lockdown, sadly, would have been nothing out of the ordinary in America, where school attacks occur almost every week. But the girl, who wore a headscarf, spoke Swedish, and was standing next to her father outside an elementary and middle school in normally peaceful Trollhättan, an industrial town about fifty miles north of Gothenburg. She blinked and looked down a few times as her father described how he had come running when his daughter had called, crying and pleading with him to hurry. He pointed to his feet: he was still in his shower sandals.</p>
 <p>The attack has stunned Sweden, where <a href="https://www.bra.se/bra/bra-in-english/home/crime-and-statistics.html" target="_blank">violent crime is rare</a>, and the last reported school attack was in 1961. Children often walk unaccompanied to school, where main entrances are usually unlocked and unguarded, allowing anyone to enter. This might be perceived as naive or even dangerous in another country, but in Sweden it is part of a very conscious and deeply rooted practice of keeping society open and accessible to its citizens.</p>
 <p>The twenty-one-year-old killer was a native Swede named Anton Lundin Pettersson, and according to witnesses he arrived at the school in a black trench coat, a face mask, and a black helmet and stabbed his victims with a large knife. After attacking an Iraqi-born teacher’s aide, at the school entrance, he appeared to have deliberately avoided fair-skinned students. Instead, he marched on until he found and killed a Somali-born fifteen-year-old and severely injured a recently arrived Syrian teenager, according to Swedish police. Shortly after, police gunned down the attacker, who died at a local hospital. He left behind a letter stating his reasons for the attack, police said, which makes clear that it was a racially motivated hate crime.</p>
 <p>Unlike <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-14259989" target="_blank">Anders Behring Breivik</a>, the Norwegian extremist who killed sixty-nine people at a summer camp, in 2011, and was charged with terrorism, Lundin Pettersson did not carry a gun, which likely would have led to a larger death toll. He was, however, one in the familiar pattern of an isolated young man who spent much of his time online, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/HiphopDestroyer666" target="_blank">leaving traces</a> of his interest in Nazi Germany and far-right, anti-immigrant ideology.</p>
 <p>Before it was taken down, his Facebook profile showed just a handful of friends and the logo of the German heavy-metal band Rammstein, which has been accused of racist and fascist sympathies. Only hours after Lundin Pettersson was identified as the attacker, right-wing fan groups appeared online, heralding him as someone who defended his country from racial integration. Trollhättan is the <a href="https://politologerna.wordpress.com/2013/11/07/sveriges-mest-segregerade-kommuner/" target="_blank">most segregated</a> city in Sweden, according to Swedish political scientists: in the school’s neighborhood, half of the population is foreign-born.</p>
 <p>The attack cut right into what has been described as an <a href="http://www.worldpoliticsreview.com/articles/16955/open-and-shut-swedens-identity-crisis" target="_blank">identity crisis</a> for social democratic Sweden, which has long been the <a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/graphicdetail/2015/09/daily-chart" target="_blank">top recipient</a> of asylum seekers per capita in Europe, and has prided itself on a humanitarian approach to the current refugee crisis. Even as some of the most generous European countries, such as Germany, have <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/10/16/world/europe/migrant-crisis-europe.html" target="_blank">taken steps</a> to tighten asylum procedures and limit what migration experts call “the pull factor,” Sweden has left its southern border largely open and has stood by a broad interpretation of the <a href="http://www.unhcr.org/pages/49da0e466.html" target="_blank">United Nations refugee convention</a>, accepting <a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/graphicdetail/2015/09/daily-chart" target="_blank">three out of every four</a> asylum seekers. The <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/europes-crisis-of-conscience" target="_blank">lack of a coherent European system</a> for handling asylum seekers, a breakdown of the continent’s internal and external border controls, and the recent deterioration of Afghanistan have contributed to the influx of migrants to Sweden in recent months, as has Sweden’s policy, unique in Europe, of extending permanent residency to Syrians applying for asylum.</p>
 <p>In a rather homogenous country of only nine and a half million people, <a href="http://www.oecd.org/migration/integration-indicators-2012/keyindicatorsbycountry/name,218347,en.htm" target="_blank">fourteen per cent of the population</a> is now foreign-born, and the number is expected to rise. The school killings occurred only hours after the government <a href="http://www.migrationsverket.se/English/About-the-Migration-Agency.html" target="_blank">agency for migration</a> <a href="http://sverigesradio.se/sida/artikel.aspx?programid=83&amp;artikel=6284469" target="_blank">announced</a> that a hundred and ninety thousand asylum seekers could arrive in Sweden this year, almost triple the previous estimate and far surpassing the number of people who sought refuge in Sweden during the Balkan wars.</p>
 <p>The ongoing arrival of about fifteen hundred asylum seekers each day has already caused a domestic political crisis. More than a dozen asylum centers have been set on fire in recent months, and the Sweden Democrats, a populist anti-immigrant party, have been rapidly gaining popularity, according to <a href="http://uk.reuters.com/article/2015/08/20/uk-sweden-politics-poll-idUKKCN0QP0Q120150820" target="_blank">recent polls</a>. The weak green-left coalition government has been forced to reënter negotiations over immigration with the center-right opposition, agreeing to some compromises in order to retain control. On Thursday, when the school attack occurred, Swedish Prime Minister Stefan Löfven abruptly left those talks to speak to victims and their families in Trollhättan.</p>
 <p>The Swedish historian <a href="http://www.larstragardh.se/en/" target="_blank">Lars Trägårdh</a> perhaps best described the situation when he <a href="http://sverigesradio.se/sida/artikel.aspx?programid=1637&amp;artikel=6277608" target="_blank">told Swedish Radio</a> last week that the country is experiencing a clash of ideals. The traditional Swedish ideal and self-image have revolved around a pride in and recognition of the nation-state, where citizens work hard and pay taxes. But a more recently developed Swedish ideal, held by many, has more of a universal human-rights focus that sometimes places the instinct to help as many refugees as possible ahead of the traditional priorities of a nation-state, such as securing high employment levels, insuring housing and social welfare for existing citizens, and protecting its borders.</p>
 <p>With its large foreign-aid contributions, its stated <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/swedens-feminist-foreign-minister">feminist foreign policy</a>, as well as the open door to migrants and refugees, the Swedish government likes to boast about being a “<a href="http://sverigesradio.se/sida/artikel.aspx?programid=2054&amp;artikel=6091340" target="_blank">humanitarian superpower</a>.” That self-image—and, understandably, the discomfort around having an openly anti-immigrant party in parliament—has unfortunately caused Swedish politicians across the spectrum to, until recently, largely avoid debate around the sensitive issue of immigration, and whether there may be limits to what Sweden can handle, out of fear of being accused of aligning themselves with the far right.</p>
 <p>Now the country will also have to process the trauma of what may ultimately be labelled an act of domestic terrorism. Certainly, there will be calls for increased openness and tolerance, to powerfully manifest against racism, xenophobia, and hatred, along the lines of Norway’s Jens Stoltenberg’s <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/europe/norway/9418144/Jens-Stoltenberg-interview-prime-minister-at-the-helm-during-Breivik-shooting.html" target="_blank">bold approach</a> to the Breivik attacks. But there will also be those who say that the small, wealthy nation needs to take a more cautious approach to immigration, in order to preserve its citizens’ faith in the traditional social contract while maintaining a strong humanitarian ideal. What the U.N.H.C.R. calls the <a href="http://www.unhcr.org/558193896.html" target="_blank">largest refugee crisis</a> of all time may also be Sweden’s most painful and complicated political struggle in the next decade, and a very personal one for many Swedes.</p>
]]>
</description>
<link>http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/an-attack-and-an-identity-crisis-in-sweden</link>
</item>
<item>
<title>B.M.W.D.</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p class=\"descender\"><p>A day’s gone by since the Mets’ four-game sweep of the Cubs in the National League Championships and their glide into the coming World Series, but reality still feels a little distance away. “Beyond my wildest dreams” is the consensus summary among some old Mets fans I’ve consulted. We should not have been surprised by this morning’s baseball news, then, when Commissioner Rob Manfred swiftly accepted an offer from the International Rescue Committee to guarantee Cubs left fielder Kyle Schwarber an early safe passage into the American League, where he will no doubt find employment as a designated hitter. He will leave his mitt at the border.</p>
 <p>Similarly if less dramatically comes word that Manfred, known for his concern for the fans, has arranged a meeting between TBS baseball broadcaster Ernie Johnson, Jr., and the National Institute of Mental Health, with full expectation that Johnson will enter therapy to overcome his fixed need to say “bag” when he means “base,” and “knock” when he means “hit” or “base hit.”</p>
 <p>Less certain yet are talks between M.L.B. and the Esurance insurance company’s advertising people, but expectation lingers that fans will soon be guaranteed no more than an every-other-day screening of the ad depicting Giants catcher Buster Posey, in full pads and uni, in a maternity ward, where he offers to help deliver the baby of an imminently expectant mom.</p>
 <p>Well, maybe.</p>
 <p>Let’s listen, rather, to the actual words of my friend and lifelong Mets fan Nick, a bookseller in Down East Maine, when he talked to me yesterday about the final Mets-Cubs game on Wednesday night, out at Wrigley Field. “Nothing about this seems quite right,” he said, almost querulously. “When Matz gives up his first hit, in the fourth inning, I’m thinking, Shit, we’re going to lose this. I mean, hello—we’re up six-oh there, and a normal man would be thinking, Well, they were always going to get some hits sometime. But no, not me. All the games felt like that.”</p>
 <p>Nick relaxed a little later that evening and went outside to tamp down the last embers of the leaf fire he’d had going in his back yard. “A nice night and pretty warm,” he said. “Eighth inning and I’m in my boxers and clogs and a T-shirt, and when I come back in Mariah says, ‘Well, you missed it.’ Daniel Murphy’s fourth homer [of the N.L.C.S.], she means. Typical.”</p>
 <p>Another witness, a semi-Metsophile, a schoolteacher named Peggy, said, “I love Murphy and Granderson, because when something good happens they actually smile. It’s nothing like this angry tough-guy look and punching the air that everyone else keeps doing. That never used to happen.”</p>
 <p>My friend Mark and his teen-age son Paul make little baseball bets all summer long, sometimes in person but also over the phone. (“A lot of trust there,” Mark said.) Paul gets all three N.L. division winners right, and by the time the championship series comes along Mark is down by forty-one dollars. “I’m trying to catch up,” he told me, “and in the bottom of the fifth&nbsp;inning of that second&nbsp;game against the Cubs I bet him three bucks that our pitcher Syndergaard&nbsp;will go at least eight. Two outs later he’s gone, out of the game.</p>
 <p>“I’m a real Mets fan—by now both Paul and I are sleeping in our Mets caps, and on Monday, the off day, he gives me a Murphy T-shirt for my birthday—and I’ve only bet against them technically. The last afternoon I call him and say that I’ll bet three dollars and lay ten-to-one odds he doesn’t hit another dinger in Game Four. Paul says, ‘Oh, Papa, I can’t do that, it’s so unfair to you.’ I’m thinking, Nice boy, but I hope he won’t go through life like this. We settle on five to one.</p>
 <p>“After Murphy’s fourth at-bat in that game, when he hits a double off the wall, I send Paul a text: ‘Whew! THAT was close!’ Then when Murphy goes deep on his next I send him—well, I won’t say what I sent but Paul doesn’t mind, he knows me. I’m down fifty-nine bucks. Game Four also happens to be Paul’s seventeenth birthday, and he says it’s his happiest one ever.”</p>
 <p>Payne, a lawyer, said, “When they won we jumped up and down a lot, but I still can’t get used to it. If this is reality, the Cubs would have scored about eighteen runs in any inning. Otherwise, it’s a dream.”</p>
 <p>His wife, Belle, had different problems. “You know how it’s been with me and the Mets all these years,” she said, “but what you may not remember is that I’ve never been able to <em>st</em>and&nbsp;Daniel Murphy. He’s a Jesus freak and a gay-basher and not a good infielder. Every time he hit one of those homers this week I’d hear on the phone from our friend Kent, and we’d say, ‘There he goes again.’ We said he was on J-roids.”</p>
 <p>She went on, “I can’t take all this in. I’m confused. Now Murphy’s going to make a whole lot of money and we won’t be able to afford him. Maybe he’ll go to the Yankees—they deserve each other.”</p>
 <p>Belle seemed to grow a fraction brighter when she talked about earlier days this summer: “Friday, July 24th, and Payne and I are at Jacob deGrom T-Shirt Night at Citi Field against the Dodgers. Niese is pitching and he gives up six runs in the first three innings. It’s the worst game I ever saw—seven–two in the end, I think—and we actually left before it was over. I’m wearing a Bovina T-shirt.” Belle and Payne have a weekend house in Bovina, N.Y. “And somebody near us in the stands sees it and says, ‘Hey, I know that place,’ and pretty soon everybody around us joins in, even the venders. Anything not to talk about the Mets. A few days later, Sandy”—Alderson, the Mets general manager—“makes all those trades, and everything’s changed.”</p>
 <p>Soon she was back in the present, “Tuesday’s the first game of the World Series, and we have tickets to ‘Tannhäuser’ at the Met. Four and a half hours, with two intermissions, so we won’t see a single inning. The tickets are really expensive and I’d trade them in in a minute, but now of course nobody will want them. All this is a huge adjustment for me. I’m trying to get used to it, and it’s so fun.”</p>
]]>
</description>
<link>http://www.newyorker.com/news/sporting-scene/mets-fans-wildest-dreams</link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Daily Cartoon: Friday, October 23rd</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[]]>
</description>
<link>http://www.newyorker.com/cartoons/daily-cartoon/friday-october-23rd-hillary-clinton-benghazi-congressional-hearing</link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Are Cats Domesticated?</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p class=\"descender\"><p>“The cat does not offer services,” William Burroughs wrote. “The cat offers itself.” But it does so with unapologetic ambivalence. Greet a cat enthusiastically and it might respond with nothing more than a few unhurried blinks. Later, as you’re trying to work, it will commandeer your lap, keyboard, and attention, purring all the while. A cat will mew at the food bowl in the morning and set off on a multiple-day trek in the afternoon. Dogs are dependent on us to the point of being obsequious, but cats seem to be constantly reëvaluating the merits of our relationship, as well as their role in domestic life. “Are cats domesticated?” is one of the most frequently Googled questions about the animals, based on the search engine’s autocomplete suggestions.</p>
 <p>It’s a question that scientists have been asking, too. The latest answer, based on insights from recent archeological discoveries and genome-sequencing studies, is that cats are semi-domesticated. Conventional wisdom holds that the ancient Egyptians were the first people to bond with the cat, only four thousand years ago. In 2004, however, a team of French researchers working in Cyprus unearthed the ninety-five-hundred-year-old remains of a human and a cat buried side by side. Last year, an analysis of cat bones and teeth from a fifty-three-hundred-year-old settlement in China indicated that the animals were eating rodents, grains, and the leftovers of human meals. It appears that, following the advent of agriculture, wildcats in the Near East and Asia likely began to congregate near farms and grain stores, where mice and rats were abundant. People tolerated the volunteer exterminators, and wildcats became increasingly comfortable with people. Whether this affiliation began five or ten millennia ago, the evidence suggests that cats have not been part of our domestic domain for nearly as long as dogs, who have been our companions for perhaps forty thousand years.</p>
 <p>At first, the cat was yet another opportunistic creature that evolved to take advantage of civilization. It was essentially a larger version of the rodents it caught. Somewhere along the line, people shifted from tolerating cats to welcoming them, providing extra food and a warm place to sleep. Why? Perhaps because of the cat’s innate predisposition to tameness and its inherent faunal charm—what the Japanese would call&nbsp;<em>kawaii</em>. Look up photos of the thirty-eight or so wildcat species and you might be surprised at how easy it is to picture one curled up on the couch. Dogs likely initiated their own domestication, too, by prowling around campfires in search of food scraps. Whereas our ancestors quickly harnessed dogs to useful tasks, breeding them to guard, hunt, and herd, they never asked much of cats. We have also been slow to diversify cat breeds. Many dog, horse, and cattle breeds are more than five hundred years old, but the first documented cat fanciers’ show didn’t take place until 1871, at the Crystal Palace, in London, and the most modern cat breeds emerged only&nbsp;within the past fifty years.</p>
 <p>This relatively short and lenient period of selective breeding is manifest in the cat genome, Wesley Warren, a geneticist at Washington University in St. Louis*, said. In a study published last year, Warren and his colleagues analyzed DNA from several wildcats and domestic cat breeds, including an Abyssinian named Cinnamon. They confirmed that, genetically, cats have diverged much less from their wildcat ancestors than dogs have from wolves, and that the cat genome has much more modest signatures of artificial selection. Because cats also retain sharper hunting skills than dogs, abandoned felines are more likely to survive without any human help. And in some countries, feral cats routinely breed with their wildcat cousins. “There’s still a lot of genetic mixing,” Warren said. “You don’t have the true differentiation you see between wolf and dog. Using the dog as the best comparison, the modern cat is not what I would call fully domesticated.”</p>
 <p>Not all researchers agree. “I don’t think it makes sense to talk about animals as semi- or fully domesticated,” Greger Larson, a paleogeneticist and archeologist at Oxford University and an expert on domestication, said. “Any threshold you try to define will necessarily be arbitrary.” Larson tends to agree with the views of Melinda Zeder, an archeologist at the Smithsonian Institute, who has written extensively on the domestication of both plants and animals. Zeder characterized domestication as an ongoing symbiosis between humans and another species—“a sort of pact that ends up being mutually beneficial,” she said. This relationship, she argued, can follow many paths and result in somewhat different outcomes, which she has catalogued. Sometimes people gradually domesticate a prey species—sheep, goats, cattle—or deliberately remove non-prey animals from the wild and breed them for a specific purpose, as we’ve done with horses. In other cases, hunger draws a wild animal—dogs, chickens, guinea pigs, cats—to human society, where it becomes increasingly tolerant of people. Even a single domestic lineage can contain varying degrees of dependency and a range of temperaments.</p>
 <p>“Cats are domesticated,” Zeder said. “But I think what confuses people about cats is that they still carry some of the more aloof behaviors of their solitary wild progenitors. Sometimes they don’t give a damn about you, but they are very much part of your niche. Cats have us do everything for them. We clean their litter, stroke them, admire them, but unlike dogs they do not have to constantly please and satisfy our needs. They are probably the ultimate domesticate.”</p>
 <p>When I was growing up in California, I had a tuxedo cat named Jasmine. When I called her, she would sometimes stop in place and stare at me for a few minutes before trotting over, as though she needed to preserve the pretense that this meeting was entirely her idea. She was incredibly affectionate when she wanted to be, but she spent most of her time in solitude. Like so many of her ilk, she loved to perch herself on or a near a windowsill, surveying the outdoors for hours. It strikes me now how quintessentially feline that behavior is: a docile carnivore balanced on the border of a human home, alone and content, yet with all its senses tuned to the world beyond.</p>
 <p><em>*Correction: An earlier version of this post misidentified Wesley Warren’s university affiliation.</em></p>
]]>
</description>
<link>http://www.newyorker.com/tech/elements/are-cats-domesticated</link>
</item>
<item>
<title>To Catch a Falling Leaf</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[]]>
</description>
<link>http://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/to-catch-a-falling-leaf</link>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Provoked Palestinian Knife Attacks in Israel?</title>
<description>
<![CDATA[<p class=\"descender\"><p>This past Saturday, in separate incidents, four young Palestinians—three of them teen-agers—were shot dead after knife attacks on Israelis, three on police, one on an armed settler. Since the beginning of October, ten Israelis and dozens of Palestinians have been killed in attacks or suspected attacks, or confrontations at street demonstrations. Many more on both sides have been wounded. “These random, unpredictable attacks have stumped Israeli police,” CNN <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2015/10/14/middleeast/israel-palestinian-tensions/">reported</a> last Thursday, just after police killed a young Palestinian man, dressed in combat fatigues, who had attempted a stabbing near the Damascus Gate of Jerusalem’s Old City. Israeli authorities, the report continued, could not find any connection between the attackers and organized groups such as Hamas and Fatah, and so found it “difficult to devise a streamlined strategy to fight them.”</p>
 <p>The attacks have targeted soldiers, police, and Jewish civilians, most often in and around the Old City—where the Haram al-Sharif, or Temple Mount, has been increasingly contested by rogue zealot members of Benjamin Netanyahu’s Cabinet—but also near West Bank settlements, especially around Hebron, and in Israeli cities as far away as Beersheba. Last Friday, about a hundred Palestinians torched Joseph’s Tomb, in Nablus, as if answering last February’s “<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/fear-of-a-third-intifada">price tag</a>” torching of a mosque by Jewish settlers in Al-Jaba’ah, near Bethlehem. In Jerusalem, Mayor Nir Barkat, who wrestled a would-be attacker to the ground in February, has called for new police checkpoints to monitor the comings and goings from Arab neighborhoods, and for all Israeli Jewish citizens to arm themselves. The centrist leader Yair Lapid, otherwise stridently secular, has found inspiration in Talmudic precepts: “The rabbis teach that if someone comes up against you to kill you, you should kill him first,” he said. “That should be our working model.” He <a href="http://www.haaretz.com/opinion/.premium-1.680706">added</a>, “Don’t hesitate. Even at the start of an attack, shooting to kill is correct. If someone is brandishing a knife, shoot him. It’s part of Israel’s deterrence.”</p>
 <p>These horrible attacks have left Israelis questioning whether the violence is a new Palestinian uprising, incited by a weakened, opportunistic Palestinian Authority—if not directly led by underground Hamas cells—or, rather, a passing expression of rage by Palestinian youth. Social-media posts have encouraged Palestinians to participate in the “Knife Intifada,” and have even given instructions on how to stab victims. President Mahmoud Abbas has condemned the violence in vague terms, and the attack on Joseph’s Tomb more pointedly. In 2011, he told me he would “<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/02/13/magazine/13Israel-t.html?_r=0" target="_blank">never</a>” return to armed struggle. But he has seemed to signal tolerance for these new attacks. On September 16th, Abbas said on Palestinian television, “We welcome every drop of blood spilled in Jerusalem. This is pure blood, clean blood, blood on its way to Allah.” Two weeks later, the stabbings began. One cannot help but be reminded of the grotesque suicide bombings of the al-Aqsa Intifada, which began almost exactly fifteen years ago.</p>
 <p>Now as then, parents are keeping their children away from shopping malls, and guards are appearing at the entrances to restaurants. It is impossible, especially for those of us who have lost loved ones to terror, to see the knifings and hear talk of martyrs and not respond with instinctive revulsion. But there are proximate causes, and then there are material ones. Today’s attacks may appear “random” and “unpredictable,” but an increase in their incidence and intensity is entirely <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/slipping-the-terror-trap">predictable</a><strong>.</strong> In 2012, the Association for Civil Rights in Israel found that eighty-four per cent of Arab children in East Jerusalem <a href="http://www.ynetnews.com/articles/0,7340,L-4660616,00.html" target="_blank">fell below</a> the poverty line. The unemployment rate among Arabs in the city was about forty per cent among men and eighty-five per cent among women, <em>Haaretz</em> reported in 2012. Three hundred and twenty thousand Arabs live in East Jerusalem—although estimates vary depending on the inclusion of neighborhoods behind the separation wall—and constitute about thirty-eight per cent of the total population. Arab residents of East Jerusalem have no Israeli citizenship, only permanent-residency cards, which means that they are eligible for medical insurance and also have to pay Israeli taxes. They do not vote in national elections, though Israeli governments have claimed the united city as the country’s capital. Then there are the open provocations: not only the public agitation by government ministers for equal Jewish access to the Haram al-Sharif but also the encroachment by rightist archeological organizations on the neighborhood of Silwan, and the marches by tens of thousands of radical nationalist yeshiva students through Nablus Gate on Jerusalem Day.</p>
 <p>But the statistics and political encroachments, however dramatic, do not fully capture the ambient pressure on Arab families—the humiliating limitations that steer most Jerusalem Arabs, no matter their intelligence or ambition, to the counters of delis and the steering wheels of delivery trucks. A number of highly educated Arabs find medical positions in Jerusalem’s hospitals or management positions in its hotels. They testify to the possibility of coexistence. They are also anomalous. A 2013 United Nations <a href="http://www.un.org/depts/dpa/qpal/docs/2014Ankara/P2%20MAHMOUD%20ELKHAFIF%20gdsapp2012d1_en.pdf" target="_blank">report</a> found that more than half of employed Arabs work in “services, commerce, hotels, and restaurants,” and another quarter in construction and agriculture. In 2008, I told the story of <a href="http://articles.latimes.com/2008/jul/10/opinion/oe-avashai10">Abed</a>, who stayed in Jerusalem to marry, and hoped to start a business during the heady days of the Oslo peace process. He ended up running the meat department of our local supermarket and, after twenty years, had saved enough to build a stately home in a northern suburb. But then the separation wall, begun in 2002, put his new house beyond his reach, in so-called Palestinian territory. If Abed occupied it, he would lose his Jerusalem residency and health insurance; he had less than a week to move his family of five into a two-room apartment. (“It is a home for the birds now,” he told me, adding, “Bless God,” his eyes welling with tears.) Abed’s brother then tried to expand his home in the mixed neighborhood of Abu Tor, but was denied a permit, again and again. He put on an addition anyway, as Jews often do, and Jerusalem authorities demolished the entire house. More recently, Abed considered opening a fish store on the commercial street where he has worked for a generation. (I helped him with the business plan.) But he soon determined that an Arab could not hope to get kosher certification or a loan from Israeli banks—and no Arab banks are permitted to operate in the city. I have not seen Abed’s son, who is now a teen-ager, since he was a toddler. But I can only imagine the sting he has felt watching his father go off to work each day. Multiply such a sting by many thousands.</p>
 <p>Jeffrey Goldberg <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2015/10/the-roots-of-the-palestinian-uprising-against-israel/410944/" target="_blank">has written</a>, in <em>The Atlantic,</em> that the real provocation for the knife attacks is a century-old “Palestinian narrative, one that obviates the possibility of a solution that allows Jews national and religious equality.” He compares the blood in the streets now to the blood in the streets in the nineteen-twenties, when the mufti of Jerusalem, Amin al-Husseini, incited attacks against Jews in response to their claim to the Western Wall. But then as now, Arabs were responding not just to what was in the air but what was on the ground: there was the British occupation, which, breaking earlier promises, was preëmpting Arab independence by incubating “the Jewish national home”; there were the massive Zionist land purchases from absentee landlords, which were displacing thousands of peasant farmers; there were the Labor Zionist policies excluding Arab labor from Hebrew-speaking enterprises. And, as the historian Hillel Cohen has shown, Jewish religious leaders in 1929, unlike Muslim leaders at that time, refused to acknowledge that their rites—such as the “March of the Flags” to commemorate Tisha B’Av, the fast day marking the destruction of the temple—could be provocative, or the violence mounting on both sides. Goldberg is right that young Palestinians, who have committed horrible acts, have taken inspiration from calls to martyrdom. But he might also ask why those calls have landed on such impressionable ears.</p>
 <p>This is just what Benjamin Netanyahu seems determined not to do. On Wednesday, he aggravated the situation beyond anyone’s expectations by telling the World Zionist Congress, in Jerusalem, that it was the mufti who gave Adolf Hitler the idea for the Final Solution.&nbsp;“Haj Amin al-Husseini went to Hitler and said, ‘If you expel them, they’ll all come here,’ ” Netanyahu said. “So what should I do with them?” Hitler asked Husseini, in Netanyahu’s account. “He said, ‘Burn them.’ ” Opposition leader Isaac Herzog and others harshly criticized Netanyahu for this claim, accusing him of giving comfort to Holocaust deniers. Netanyahu responded that he did not intend to absolve Hitler “but rather to show that the forefathers of the Palestinian nation, without a country and without a so-called occupation, without land and without settlements, even then aspired to systematic incitement to exterminate the Jews.”</p>
 <p>With these words, Netanyahu carries Goldberg’s reasonable caution to a grotesque extreme. He is presenting the current attacks as evidence of the hopelessness of ever looking for a Palestinian partner—presumably justifying, among other things, his government’s settlement project (which Palestinians view as incitement). The violence, in Netanyahu’s view, should be understood as an&nbsp;inevitability more than a century old, the consequence of a permanent, religious-inflected national ideology. The inference is that Israelis should take up arms and put aside illusions. On Thursday morning, John Kerry met with Netanyahu in Berlin and emerged expressing “a cautious measure of optimism” in advance of meetings with Abbas and Jordan’s King Abdullah in Amman, tomorrow. Presumably, Kerry is now focussed on reaching an agreement about the status of the Temple Mount. Netanyahu did not miss the chance to say, again, that the attacks are “driven directly by incitement, incitement from Hamas, incitement from the Islamist movement in Israel, and incitement, I am sorry to say, from President Abbas and the Palestinian Authority.” He is, of course, right. The incitement must stop. It must also be situated in a widening tragedy that produces despair.</p>
]]>
</description>
<link>http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/what-provoked-palestinian-knife-attacks-in-israel</link>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
