<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="0.92" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <channel>

 	<title>The New Yorker</title>

 	<link>http://www.newyorker.com</link>

 	<description>Online version of the weekly magazine, with current articles, cartoons, blogs, audio, video, slide shows, an archive of articles and abstracts back to 1925.</description>

 	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2015 22:30:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>

 	<docs>http://backend.userland.com/rss092</docs>

 	<language>en-US</language>

 

 	<!-- generator="WordPress/4.3.1" -->

 

 	<item>		<title>Telling the Truth About ISIS and Raqqa</title>		<description><![CDATA[<div><div itemprop="articleBody" class="articleBody ad-container " id="articleBody">

												<figure class="horizontal attachment-large landscape img-expandable featured">
								<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Remnick-Truth-about-ISIS-Raqqa-1200.jpg" title="Telling the Truth About ISIS and Raqqa" itemprop="url">
									<img itemprop="image" src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Remnick-Truth-about-ISIS-Raqqa-290x150-1448209111.jpg" data-src-mobile="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Remnick-Truth-about-ISIS-Raqqa-290x150-1448209111.jpg" data-src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Remnick-Truth-about-ISIS-Raqqa-690x453-1448208892.jpg" class="post-load horizontal attachment-large" alt="The group Raqqa Is Being Slaughtered Silently faces unceasing peril from ISIS as its members smuggle out information about what's happening in their city."/>								</a>

																<figcaption class="caption" itemprop="description">
									<span class="caption-text">The group Raqqa Is Being Slaughtered Silently faces unceasing peril from ISIS as its members smuggle out information about what's happening in their city.</span>									<span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">
										<span class="hideFromView">Credit</span> PHOTOGRAPH BY STRINGER / REUTERS / LANDOV									</span>								</figcaption>
															</figure>
							<a class="tny-slot" name="/2" data-total-words="0"/><a class="tny-page" name="/1" data-total-words="0"/><p class="descender" word_count="69" data-wc="69">On Saturday night, five young Syrians slouched into a dive bar in New York and ordered drinks. When the bartender asked if off-brand vodka was O.K., they had to smile. They were all exiles from Raqqa, the provincial city in northern Syria that <span class="smallcaps"><a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2015/11/30/isis-after-paris">ISIS</a></span> has made its operational center and the de-facto capital of the Islamic State. No one needed the good stuff. Just a drink would do.</p> <p word_count="122" data-wc="122">Everyone in the group works for <a href="http://www.raqqa-sl.com/en/">Raqqa Is Being Slaughtered Silently (R.B.S.S.</a>), a kind of underground journalistic-activist enterprise that, under the threat of grisly execution, smuggles images and reports on <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> from Raqqa to its allies abroad. The group’s comrades, in turn, post them on <a href="https://twitter.com/Raqqa_SL?lang=en">social media</a> and its <a href="http://www.raqqa-sl.com/en/">Web site</a>. <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> has controlled Raqqa for nearly two years and much of the foreign press looks to R.B.S.S. for first-hand reports about the daily life—and depredations—in Raqqa. And because they have dared to post reports of crucifixions, beheadings, sexual abuse, and other crimes, members of R.B.S.S., both inside the city and abroad, have been <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/the-death-of-two-syrian-journalists">murdered by <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span></a> for their work.</p> <p word_count="45" data-wc="45">Abdel Aziz al-Hamza, a slender man of twenty-four, acts as spokesperson. As recently as a few years ago, he was a biology student at Raqqa University who dreamed of studying pharmacology in Jordan or Turkey and returning home to start his career and a family.</p> <p word_count="71" data-wc="71">“I was a normal guy,” he said, after taking a first sip of his vodka-and-Sprite. “I hung out with friends at cafés and bars. None of us were political. In Syria, before the revolution, it was a crime to be political in any way.” Raqqa was a relatively prosperous city with energy resources and an agricultural base. Major dams in the area are an important source of power in Syria.</p> <p word_count="49" data-wc="49">When anti-regime demonstrations broke out in March, 2011, in Dara’a, a city in the south, and reports spread throughout Syria that Bashar al-Assad’s security forces were firing on civilians, Hamza and many others joined in protests, in Raqqa. “We wanted to be free,” he said. “It seemed simple.”</p> <p word_count="57" data-wc="57">As the uprising against Assad spread throughout Syria and the casualty counts rose, tens of thousands of people left Aleppo, Homs, Idlib, and other embattled cities and towns and arrived in Raqqa, which is on the northern bank of the Euphrates River. The city swelled and became known for a while as “the hotel of the revolution.”</p> <p word_count="43" data-wc="43">By March, 2013, Free Syrian Army (F.S.A.) troops, as well as Islamist rebel forces, including al-Nusra, controlled the city and tore down a statue of Assad’s father, Hafez al-Assad, to celebrate. “Raqqa was the first liberated city in Syria,” Hamza said.</p> <p word_count="80" data-wc="80">But at around the same time, members of <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>, or the Islamic State, bearing black flags, began accumulating in the nearby town of Slouk. “At first, there were only around fifteen people,” Hamza said. “None of us knew about it” until fighters from al-Nusra began switching over to <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>, which had its origin in Iraq. “Over time, around ninety per cent of the Nusra fighters in the area became <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>, and only ten per cent of them refused,” Hamza said.</p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/3" data-total-words="536"/><p word_count="140" data-wc="140">In May, 2013, <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> fighters started making kidnapping runs and attacking F.S.A. leaders, and, by late summer, there were full-scale battles with F.S.A. troops. As the F.S.A. began to suffer defeats, car bombings, kidnappings, and executions, one of the journalists at the table said, some F.S.A. soldiers “out of complete fear” also joined <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>. People in Raqqa could see that <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> was growing stronger, as they brought in heavy weapons from Iraq and seasoned soldiers who had fought in the Iraqi Army under Saddam Hussein. By the beginning of 2014, <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> had absolute control of the city. They now overran the mosques, drove out Christians from the city, and turned major municipal buildings into their various headquarters. The propaganda campaign that <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> mustered following the capture of Raqqa brought on a wave of foreigners.</p> <p word_count="59" data-wc="59">“No one thought about the caliphate until 2014 when they declared Raqqa the capital of the caliphate and then these guys started coming in from all around the world,” one of the R.B.S.S. journalists told me. “It was like New York! A second New York! People from Australia! From Belgium! From Germany! From France! A global tide!”</p> <p word_count="15" data-wc="15">“Maybe the next World Cup will be in Raqqa!” another of the journalists said, sarcastically.</p> <p word_count="76" data-wc="76">The young foreign fighters were, and remain, privileged characters in the city. There are thousands of them in Raqqa, one of the R.B.S.S. journalists said: “When you are on the street you see them everywhere. They love fast-food places and Internet cafés. They love Nutella and they’ve got cans of Red Bull. Chocolates! Cheesecake! People are poor and see these expensive things! But <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> wants to keep these Western recruits happy.”</p> <p id="parallax9x2_frame" data-jivox-ad-id="constellation-parallax" data-constellation-id="parallax"/><a class="tny-page" name="/2" data-total-words="826"/><p word_count="51" data-wc="51">The first crucifixion came early that spring—a horrific event to recall even now. Everyone at the table remembered the shock of it. Then came more: two people, shot in the head by <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> executioners, crucified, and left for days for all to witness in the city’s main traffic roundabout.</p> <p word_count="78" data-wc="78">“This was something new that we had never seen, this kind of violence,” Hamza said. “They started cutting heads off, crucifixions. They spread panic everywhere.” There were edicts against drinking and smoking. Enforced by an all-female morality police called the Khansaa Brigade, women were made to wear the veil and, eventually, black shoes only. They are beaten if their niqab is somehow too revealing, a veil too flimsy, or if they are caught walking on the street alone.</p> <p word_count="110" data-wc="110">“I can say that women are the people suffering the most under <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>,” one R.B.S.S. member said. “They can’t show their faces. <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> bothers them a lot. They take sticks and slash them on the street if the veil shows the eyes. They say, ‘Hey, hey, do you want to marry me?’ People have become so poor, the families so weak, that some give up their daughters to <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>. They accept it. Sometimes <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> forces them to do this. The <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/friend-flees-horror-isis">Yazidis</a>—<span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> says these people believe in Satan. And because of that their women are just traded from man to man in <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>, sold, raped, abandoned.”</p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/4" data-total-words="1065"/><p word_count="43" data-wc="43">Schools were closed down. <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>’s imams dominated the mosques. Many children were sent off to <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>’s religious institutions, where they were taught the most fanatical form of the faith, and then to military camps, the R.B.S.S. activists said.</p> <p word_count="75" data-wc="75">“Not everyone who joined <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> did it because they believe the ideology,” Hamza said. “I have a friend who is with <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> but doesn’t like <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> at all. … I called him and said, ‘Why did you join? You hate them!’ He said, ‘I am a doctor and they did not let me work. They told me, ‘If you wanted to work, you have to join us.’ I couldn’t live otherwise. I have children…’ ”</p> <p word_count="173" data-wc="173">In their recruiting, <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> targets the local youth, according to members of R.B.S.S. With schools closed down, kids play aimlessly in the street. <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> members befriend them, give them gifts, sometimes candy, sometimes a mobile phone. They ask the kids to join <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>, one R.B.S.S. member said, “But they say, ‘Don’t tell your parents.’ I know about one child who went missing for months. His parents looked and looked. Thirteen years old, a boy. Finally, the father said to an <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> leader, ‘Where is my son, I’ll give you money.’ Turns out the child was in a training camp for <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>. They kidnap these children. They are sent to a mosque for education, so they are brainwashed with an extremist form of Islam. After this, they are sent to army camp to teach them how to fight, how to make and carry bombs. At their graduation, they have orders to execute someone––sometimes a beheading, sometimes they just cut off the head of a sheep.”</p> <p word_count="68" data-wc="68">There is no easy way to check every assertion made by R.B.S.S., but the accounts of extreme cruelty that they provided consistently square with the reporting done by such journalists as <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/08/14/world/middleeast/isis-enshrines-a-theology-of-rape.html">Rukmini Callimachi</a> and <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/11/22/world/middleeast/isis-wives-and-enforcers-in-syria-recount-collaboration-anguish-and-escape.html">Azadeh Moaveni</a>, in the <em>Times</em>, <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2015/06/01/journey-to-jihad">Ben Taub in <em>The New Yorker</em></a>, and many others who have extensively interviewed <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> members and victims in Iraq, in Europe, and along the Turkish-Syrian border.</p> <p word_count="84" data-wc="84">The most powerful instrument of indoctrination for <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> is the Internet. <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> glorifies both the sanctity of its moral, historical, and political goals and its acts of vengeance against all whom it brands infidels. And it advertises it all without shame. “If you Googled ‘Raqqa’ in those early days you got their material first and only,” one of the R.B.S.S. members told me. “So that was one reason why a lot of foreign fighters emigrated. And this is why we began.”</p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/5" data-total-words="1508"/><p word_count="74" data-wc="74">In mid-April, 2014, just a month after the first crucifixions in the city, a group of six like-minded young people started to talk to each other on Facebook. The group expanded only a little before <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> discovered it. Within two or three weeks a local imam declared that anyone who worked with R.B.S.S. would be tracked down and executed. Some civilians were arrested simply because they “liked” a post on social media.</p> <p word_count="30" data-wc="30">Undaunted, R.B.S.S. activists posted on social-media sites photographs and reports of daily life in Raqqa; the whole idea was to fight <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> propaganda on the digital battlefield.</p> <p word_count="49" data-wc="49">In May, 2014, R.B.S.S. suffered its first casualty. One of the men at the bar told me: “One of our reporters was stopped at a checkpoint and his equipment was confiscated and searched.” He was held for three weeks, then executed in a public square in Raqqa.</p> <p word_count="89" data-wc="89">“In the beginning we didn’t think it was that dangerous,” Hamza said. “We didn’t think they would execute us. All of us had been arrested by the Assad regime more than once during the revolution. But after this execution we met and started to talk that we don’t want to lose anyone more and we started to think about whether we should stop. But in the end we decided that our lives were not more important than the life of our friend who had been killed.”</p> <p word_count="90" data-wc="90">Some of the R.B.S.S. activists devised what they hoped would be a safer, less traceable means of communication. Some left the city, and Syria itself, to help “from the other side.” Hamza, for one, took a bus out of Raqqa and headed for Turkey; he now lives, as do most of the others at the table, in Europe. Others left after the first execution of their comrade. They remained active, receiving photographs, video, and reports from their undercover comrades in Raqqa that they post on social media.</p> <a class="tny-page" name="/3" data-total-words="1840"/><p word_count="53" data-wc="53">The members of R.B.S.S. are utterly frustrated with the efforts of the West to defeat both Assad, who has fended off the opposition so far, and <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>, which has suffered recent losses in Iraq and Syria, but which has proved capable of <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/topics/the-attacks-in-paris">exacting suffering from Sinai to Beirut to Paris</a>.</p> <p word_count="68" data-wc="68">“The problem the Syrian people have with the United States is that we are suffering for five years with barrel bombs,” one R.B.S.S. journalist said. “Assad has killed so many innocents, and many people have lost hope. After Assad’s chemical attack, when he crossed the <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2013/05/13/the-thin-red-line-2">so-called ‘red line</a>,’ the U.S. just took the weapons. It made America look like a liar and weak.</p> <p word_count="109" data-wc="109">“When you say ‘Raqqa,’ the first thing people think of is <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>,” he continued. “They forget hundreds of thousands of civilians, normal people like us. I am not a terrorist. There are so many people, normal people, who want to live in a free, democratic Syria. We want to rebuild Syria, and the only way we can do it is through our civil-society group and others like it. If the United States government and other governments want to fight <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> on social media, their Twitter accounts are seen as propaganda. But when real life is shown through us, and you see what life is like, normal people believe it.”</p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/6" data-total-words="2070"/><p word_count="35" data-wc="35">Talking over the jukebox din and the raucous Saturday night conversations at the bar, Hamza asked that Americans try to imagine a city in which “the 9/11s keep happening month after month, year after year.”</p> <p word_count="104" data-wc="104">“Daily life is twenty-four-seven warplanes over your head,” another member said. “People now feel more afraid about the idea that all over the world they want to bomb this small city. People are afraid. The city of Kubani is completely destroyed. The people of Raqqa don’t want that. We love our city. The West says, ‘Let’s get the people out and bomb <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>.’ They can’t. It’s a big prison. Women under forty-five can’t leave without special permission. It’s a tribal area, and females can’t leave without men. <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> uses the people of Raqqa as a human shield.”</p> <p word_count="72" data-wc="72">The R.B.S.S. members said the American fighter planes have dropped most of their bombs on targets on the outskirts of the city or they use drones to target leaders of <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span>. They claim that Russian planes, however, have hit a hospital, two critical bridges, and a university. “The problem we have with the air strikes,” one said, “is that their planes are very stupid. They’re not smart bombs.”</p> <p word_count="120" data-wc="120">The peril for the group is unceasing. When <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> arrests or executes a member of R.B.S.S.—or someone that they believe might be sympathetic to the group—they make a show of it on social media. One video, a member told me, showed “two friends of ours accused of working for us. And they don’t. <span class="smallcaps">ISIS</span> tied them to a tree and shot them. A second video shows the execution of another friend of ours accused of working for us. They strung them up in a tree in an abandoned place and shot them in the head; they made the video to say they died ‘silently.’ They are sending us messages like this all the time.”</p> <p word_count="55" data-wc="55">Hamza will soon accept an award from the Committee to Protect Journalists in the name of his comrades, living and dead. (I’m on the board of C.P.J., which arranged our meeting.) He will dedicate the award “to our martyrs,” to the “anonymous heroes” of the campaign, and to the people of Raqqa.</p> <p word_count="69" data-wc="69">“All of us get several threats daily,” Hamza said, finishing his drink. “The last threat against me was from someone in Germany. He said I would be the next one killed. But when I think about our reporters inside Raqqa, and I am outside … I live a normal life, doing normal things. Somehow, I don’t care what will happen to me. Compared to them, I am doing nothing.”</p> 						

					


 
					
					</div>
					</div>]]></description>		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/telling-the-truth-about-isis-and-raqqa</link>			</item>

 	<item>		<title>Belgian Terror: Brussels on Lockdown</title>		<description><![CDATA[<div><div itemprop="articleBody" class="articleBody ad-container " id="articleBody">

												<figure class="vertical attachment-medium portrait img-expandable featured">
								<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/AP_8370329686111-823.jpg" title="Belgian Terror: Brussels on Lockdown" itemprop="url">
									<img itemprop="image" src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/AP_8370329686111-320x448-1448138168.jpg" data-src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/AP_8370329686111-320x448-1448138168.jpg" class="post-load vertical attachment-medium" alt="As Belgian officials raised the country’s security level and undertook an extensive search for Salah Abdeslam, who participated in the Paris attacks, parts of the city of Brussels were virtually shut down."/>								</a>

																<figcaption class="caption" itemprop="description">
									<span class="caption-text">As Belgian officials raised the country’s security level and undertook an extensive search for Salah Abdeslam, who participated in the Paris attacks, parts of the city of Brussels were virtually shut down.</span>									<span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">
										<span class="hideFromView">Credit</span> Photograph by Virginia Mayo / AP									</span>								</figcaption>
															</figure>
							<a class="tny-slot" name="/2" data-total-words="0"/><a class="tny-page" name="/1" data-total-words="0"/><p class="descender" word_count="141" data-wc="141">On Saturday, Brussels was essentially shut down, as the Belgian Prime Minister Charles Michel warned that the threat of a terror attack was “serious and imminent.” Metal shutters and gates blocked entrances to the metro system, and locals were warned to avoid concerts, train stations, shopping malls, and other venues that see large gatherings. All restaurants and cafés were closed by 6 <small>P.M.</small> Armored vehicles rolled through the streets. Soldiers patrolled in pairs, guarding public spaces and hotels. Michel said that the decision to lock down this city of more than a million inhabitants was “based on quite precise information about the risk of an attack like the one that happened in Paris.” He clarified that the government believed that “several individuals with arms and explosives” might attack the Belgian capital, “perhaps even in several places at the same time.”</p> <p word_count="144" data-wc="144">Even in more peaceful times, Bruxelles-Midi, Belgium’s largest train station, is a difficult place to police. It has twenty-two platforms, a bus terminal, a vast main hall, and long corridors connecting it to a metro stop. A thousand trains pass through each day. On Sundays, its morning market is one of the largest in Europe. But close to midnight, the station is mostly empty, except for a few late travellers and many more people who have nowhere else to go. Between twenty and thirty federal police patrol the complex, in groups of three or four. By reputation, the station and the surrounding blocks are also frequented by criminal networks. A contact who lives in Molenbeek told me, “If you want, we can buy, tomorrow, a Kalashnikov,” nearby. The sellers, he said, “just need money. They don’t ask you what you will do.”</p> <p word_count="112" data-wc="112">In August, a twenty-five-year-old named Ayoub el-Khazzani boarded a high-speed train from Amsterdam to Paris at Bruxelles-Midi. Near the French border, he took his belongings into the restroom and emerged holding an assault rifle. He also carried a pistol, a petrol cannister, a box cutter, and two hundred and seventy rounds of ammunition. Passengers pounced on him, and nobody died. El-Khazzani’s lawyer insisted that he had found the weapons in a park near the station, where he was sleeping, and that he had merely wanted to rob the train out of hunger. But a French prosecutor pointed out that el-Khazzani had paid a hundred and forty-nine euros for a first-class ticket.</p> <p word_count="106" data-wc="106">Earlier this week, French officials said that <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/abdelhamid-abaaouds-death-in-paris">Abdelhamid Abaaoud</a>, the Belgian <small>ISIS</small> fighter behind the bloodshed in Paris, had a hand in el-Khazzani’s train journey. They also linked Abaaoud to three other foiled attacks in Belgium and France this year, all of which involved the sorts of weapons usually seen on battlefields. How Abaaoud and his collaborators procured them is not yet known. Several of the men had criminal backgrounds. This fact has been widely cited to call into question their piety; a more pragmatic concern is, with contacts in the Brussels underworld, how easily can terrorists get their hands on military-style weapons and explosives?</p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/3" data-total-words="503"/><p word_count="64" data-wc="64">A few days ago, I met a retired senior Belgian counterterrorism official outside the train station in Antwerp. He guided me to a poorly lit bar nearby; before entering, he paused to explain that it was a known gathering place for criminals from the former Yugoslavia. “Normally, in this café,” he said, “it has nothing to do with terrorism, but selling drugs and weapons.”</p> <p word_count="71" data-wc="71">The bar was nearly empty. The retired official sat with his back against the wall, facing the door. “To get an illegal weapon, you need contacts in the underworld,” he said. A pleasant woman from Eastern Europe arrived with two muddy espressos. After she left, he leaned in closer, and gestured towards the bar. “If I go to the boss, here, and ask for a weapon? No. He must know me.”</p> <p word_count="135" data-wc="135">Nils Duquet, an adviser to the Flemish Parliament on weapons trafficking, told me, “There is a caricature: you can buy a gun at every street corner in Brussels, you can find it at every tea house, or even in the market of Brussels-Midi. It’s not the case. What you need are criminal connections.” He added, “There needs to be trust. If you sell me a gun, and I get caught, I can name you. They don’t want to run that risk.” Similarly, he said, “If I buy a gun from you, and you sell me a gun that was used in a homicide before, and I’m just a robber, and I get caught, I have two problems. So there needs to be this level of trust. You don’t just get one.”</p> <p word_count="122" data-wc="122">Above ground, Belgium has a rich history of weapons production. Sixty miles east of Brussels, FN Herstal, the largest small-arms factory in Europe, has been making weapons since 1889. Today, three thousand employees manufacture some fifty models of handguns, submachine guns, rifles (both assault and bolt-action), machine guns, shotguns, and aircraft weapons systems. “We have a very good gun-making school,” Duquet told me. Until recently, “our legislation on possessing firearms was not restrictive at all,” he said. “You didn’t need a license, you just needed to show your I.D. card.” As a result, “We sort of got a reputation as a place where you could get guns easily.” Criminal networks in nearby countries often travelled to Belgium to stock their arsenals.</p> <p id="parallax9x2_frame" data-jivox-ad-id="constellation-parallax" data-constellation-id="parallax"/><a class="tny-page" name="/2" data-total-words="895"/><p word_count="92" data-wc="92">Then, in May, 2006, an eighteen-year-old skinhead bought a rifle and, citing racial motivations, shot two immigrants and a toddler on the streets of Antwerp. The attack stunned Belgian society. King Albert II sent condolences to the victims’ families, and, the following month, nationwide restrictions on gun ownership were tightened dramatically. Even so, Duquet told me, “In the criminal world, you still had the idea, well, you can still go to Belgium to buy guns.” He added, “That reputation remains, and it will get stronger and stronger each time there is an attack.”</p> <p word_count="173" data-wc="173">The preferred weapons of European terrorists—Kalashnikovs, grenades, explosives, rocket-launchers—seem incongruous with life in twenty-first-century Paris and Brussels. Still, their presence, as much as the intentions of those who wield them, shut down Belgium’s capital today. According to Duquet, the weapons “that we see in Europe right now all came from Eastern Europe and the Balkans.” After the Berlin Wall came down, large military stocks disappeared. Many of these arms ended up in African conflict zones and the Middle East, but some travelled west. Then, after years of war in the Balkans, gunrunners began transporting leftover explosives and rocket-propelled grenades to Western Europe, where they could be sold at higher prices. “We call it ‘ant trade,’ ” Duquet told me. “Like ants, they bring small pieces, one by one,” that eventually accumulate, because “Kalashnikovs are durable goods. They remain operative for many years, for decades.” He added, “With all these small, continuous, additional deliveries, the pile gets bigger and bigger and bigger and bigger and bigger. Which means the prices go down.”</p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/4" data-total-words="1160"/><p word_count="111" data-wc="111">Tracking the illicit arms trade is practically impossible, especially within the European Union’s borderless Schengen Area. “We have absolutely no idea how many illegal guns there are in Belgium,” Duquet told me. Beyond the evident need to improve intelligence-sharing across E.U. countries, Duquet said, “in our country, we don’t have a culture of data management and data registration.” He showed me a Model 10 form, which officers fill out after seizing an illegal weapon. A <a href="https://www.senate.be/www/?MIval=/Vragen/SVPrintNLFR&amp;LEG=6&amp;NR=375&amp;LANG=nl">memo</a> drafted by Jan Jambon, the Interior Minister, this April, stated, “Currently, there is no database where the forms are included. . . . It is therefore impossible to say how many weapons were seized each year.”</p> <p word_count="154" data-wc="154">Some sophisticated weapons can be neutralized—with lead in the barrel, or key components removed—making them purely decorative items. In December, 2011, a member of an Antwerp-based jihadi cell called <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2015/06/01/journey-to-jihad">Sharia4Belgium</a> bought a demilitarized Kalashnikov online, and posed with it in a video. He was arrested. “We thought it was real,” the retired counterterrorism official told me. In fact, “it was a fake.” But, according to Duquet, not all demilitarized weapons remain permanently impaired. “Some people were selling guns that were demilitarized in Slovakia, and we know a Belgian guy bought these guns to sell them here,” he told me. “And somehow, somewhere along the way, the guns got reactivated, because the procedure to demilitarize in Slovakia is not that good.” Duquet says one of those guns ended up in the hands of Amedy Coulibaly, the <small>ISIS</small> sympathizer who killed hostages in a Parisian supermarket, two days after the murders at <em>Charlie Hebdo</em>.</p> <p word_count="44" data-wc="44">This evening, it became clear that the Belgian authorities were searching for Salah Abdeslam, one of the men from Brussels implicated in the Paris attacks. He was reported to have an explosive vest, along with other weapons, whose provenance we will perhaps never know.</p> 						

					


 
					
					</div>
					</div>]]></description>		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/belgian-terror-brussels-on-lockdown</link>			</item>

 	<item>		<title>Jindal Returns Seventy Dollars Raised for Presidential Campaign</title>		<description><![CDATA[<div><div itemprop="articleBody" class="articleBody ad-container " id="articleBody">

												<figure class="horizontal attachment-large landscape img-expandable featured">
								<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Borowitz-Payback-Time-1200.jpg" title="Jindal Returns Seventy Dollars Raised for Presidential Campaign" itemprop="url">
									<img itemprop="image" src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Borowitz-Payback-Time-290x150-1448124655.jpg" data-src-mobile="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Borowitz-Payback-Time-290x150-1448124655.jpg" data-src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Borowitz-Payback-Time-690x476-1448124385.jpg" class="post-load horizontal attachment-large" alt=""/>								</a>

																<figcaption class="caption" itemprop="description">
																		<span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">
										<span class="hideFromView">Credit</span> Photograph by Joe Raedle / Getty									</span>								</figcaption>
															</figure>
							<a class="tny-slot" name="/2" data-total-words="0"/><a class="tny-page" name="/1" data-total-words="0"/><p word_count="29" data-wc="29">BATON ROUGE (<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/humor/borowitz-report" target="_blank">The Borowitz Report</a>)—Just days after withdrawing from the 2016 Presidential race, Louisiana governor Bobby Jindal said that he would return the seventy dollars raised by his campaign.</p> <p word_count="21" data-wc="21">Speaking to reporters in Baton Rouge, Jindal said he was proud that his campaign war chest “came entirely from small donors.”</p> <p word_count="27" data-wc="27">“This wasn’t a campaign financed by fat cats,” he said. “We raised all of our funds from nine small donors, for an average of $7.78 per donor.”</p> <p word_count="32" data-wc="32">He bemoaned the high costs of running a political campaign in the current environment, however, and acknowledged that his staff was never able to acquire the replacement toner cartridge that they needed.</p> 						

					


 
					
					</div>
					</div>]]></description>		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/humor/borowitz-report/jindal-returns-seventy-dollars-raised-for-presidential-campaign</link>			</item>

 	<item>		<title>Our Updated Dinner-Conversation Policies</title>		<description><![CDATA[<div><div itemprop="articleBody" class="articleBody ad-container " id="articleBody">

												<figure class="vertical attachment-medium landscape img-expandable featured">
								<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Weiner-Updated-Dinner-Conversation-Policies-1200.jpg" title="Our Updated Dinner-Conversation Policies" itemprop="url">
									<img itemprop="image" src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Weiner-Updated-Dinner-Conversation-Policies-290x150-1448037059.jpg" data-src-mobile="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Weiner-Updated-Dinner-Conversation-Policies-290x150-1448037059.jpg" data-src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Weiner-Updated-Dinner-Conversation-Policies-320.jpg" class="post-load vertical attachment-medium" alt=""/>								</a>

																<figcaption class="caption" itemprop="description">
																		<span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">
										<span class="hideFromView">Credit</span> PHOTOGRAPH BY MARTIN PARR / MAGNUM									</span>								</figcaption>
															</figure>
							<a class="tny-slot" name="/2" data-total-words="0"/><a class="tny-page" name="/1" data-total-words="0"/><p word_count="3" data-wc="3">Dear Dinner Guest,</p> <p word_count="31" data-wc="31">Welcome to our home. Please take a moment to review our latest statement regarding so-called micro-aggressions, together with a revised list of “trigger warning” requests. Kindly commit the following to memory.</p> <p word_count="1" data-wc="1"><strong>MICRO-AGGRESSIONS</strong></p> <p word_count="36" data-wc="36">Micro-aggressions are things you say, imply, or otherwise convey by word or tone that we find threatening, demeaning, or insulting. Below are our three most recent examples. (A complete list is available on our Web site.)</p> <ol word_count="211" data-wc="211"> <li>One of us (Elizabeth, after a recent haircut) has been told quite a lot lately that she resembles the actress Madeleine Stowe. At such times, the reactions of others (“Who?”; “Whoa, what’s she up to these days?”) have been felt as negatively impactful, suggesting that Elizabeth herself is experiencing some kind of personal or career eclipse. For this reason, no mention of Madeleine Stowe will be tolerated until further notice.</li> <li>Both of us have, for years, been made to feel alienated or “lesser” by someone asserting (usually indirectly) that he or she is a better cook than either of us. Therefore, when dinner is served, be advised that we construe such remarks as “I’ve always liked this” or “Oh, yay!” to imply that we are incapable of preparing more than a limited number of recipes, over and over. Such patently hurtful speech will result in the immediate confiscation of the dinner in question, followed by its substitution by a bowl of corn flakes, to be served with a suitably sarcastic “Here. Enjoy.”</li> <li>Sincere compliments concerning our personal appearance are always welcome. However, tones of surprise, as in such comments as “Hey, you look great!” or “Nice!” suggest a preëxisting <em>lesser</em> opinion, and are therefore deemed to be wounding.</li> </ol> <p word_count="2" data-wc="2"><strong>TRIGGER WARNINGS</strong></p> <p word_count="39" data-wc="39">Trigger warnings are alerts that we ask you to issue in the event that you choose to discuss certain subjects that might trigger unwelcome memories, emotions, insecurities, or fears. Our latest roster of such problematic topics includes the following:</p> <ol word_count="215" data-wc="215"> <li>The designated hitter: this is something one of us (William) feels especially strongly about. Over the years, he has come, more and more, to despise the D.H.—a fact that some have noted is all the more striking, considering that we live in a National League city. To spare him any discomfort, we ask that you warn of any intention you may have of speaking in its favor—at which time William will choose either to leave the room or the house itself (weather permitting).</li> <li>After four years of marriage, we recently discovered that we had each had, in our twenties, a bad experience involving men’s cologne. We therefore require that you warn us if you feel the need to praise cologne, aftershave, “body scent,” etc., in which case we will both retreat to the kitchen and begin loudly to wash the dishes.</li> <li>One of us (Elizabeth) has decided that she cannot abide bestiality in the news or discussions of trigonometry. Guests tempted to speak highly of either of these things are asked first to announce their intention, so that Elizabeth need not be faced with hearing an opinion with which she disagrees proclaimed in her own home. Should you elect to continue, Elizabeth will insert her fingers in her ears and chant.</li> </ol> <a class="tny-slot" name="/3" data-total-words="538"/><p word_count="30" data-wc="30">Guests familiar with our previous trigger-warning requests regarding other distressing subjects (all-weather tires; Civil War surgical practices; the films of Ali McGraw, etc.) are reminded that they remain in effect.</p> <p word_count="22" data-wc="22">As always, at the intrusion of upsetting conversation, we reserve the right to make use of earplugs, headphones, or aircraft-carrier-grade sound-suppressing earmuffs.</p> <p word_count="10" data-wc="10">These rules remain in effect until the next posted update.</p> <p word_count="6" data-wc="6">Thank you, and enjoy your visit!</p> <p word_count="3" data-wc="3">Bill and Betsy</p> <aside class="footer-content"><p><strong>Watch:</strong> An afternoon at the Rockaway Beach Surf Club.</p>
<p class="media-cne"/>
</aside>						

					


 
					
					</div>
					</div>]]></description>		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/our-updated-dinner-conversation-policies</link>			</item>

 	<item>		<title>Boundaries and Renewal in Bosnia</title>		<description><![CDATA[<div><div itemprop="articleBody" class="articleBody ad-container " id="articleBody">

					 <figure id="gallery-3137773" class="gallery-wrapper">   <figcaption class="gallery-caption open" itemprop="description"> <div class="caption-container"><p class="caption">A view of Mount Trebević from Žuč, another hill that was a site of close combat during the war. Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina, 2014. </p> <p class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder"><span class="hideFromView">Credit</span>Photograph by Ziyah Gafić</p></div></figcaption>  </figure>  <a class="tny-slot" name="/2" data-total-words="0"/><a class="tny-page" name="/1" data-total-words="0"/><p class="descender" word_count="261" data-wc="261">In November, 1995, the <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/1999/09/20/the-next-war-2">Dayton Peace Agreement</a> brought the <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/bosnias-unending-war">Bosnian War</a> to a halt by formally dividing up the country among the warring parties. Diplomats accorded about half the territory to the Bosnian Serbs, and the other half to the Bosniaks (Muslims) and the Bosnian Croats. According to the agreement, the parties controlling these two “entities”—Republika Srpska and the Federation of Bosnia and Herzegovina—would have to govern them together as one tenuous nation. In 1996, when the two sides were still reeling from war, <small>NATO</small> peacekeepers rimmed the border between them, which was a former frontline, and there was little civilian transportation crossing back and forth. Today, the internal frontier is largely invisible—you can see on a map that the boundary ripples along in a rough parallel to Bosnia’s border, scything out a partition, but there are no actual controls or customs in place; the verdant hills of the Bosnian terrain appear to rise endlessly before you in one continuous whole. And yet, the boundary still exists. While on a reporting trip in the country this summer, I needed to travel between two major cities in the north, Banja Luka and Tuzla, but was told that taking public transport between them was difficult, as they lie on opposite sides of the entity lines—the main bus company didn’t even cover the route, and there were a few smaller lines that went only late at night. It might even be easier to trace my way back five hours south to Sarajevo, the capital, and depart northward again from there.</p> <p word_count="259" data-wc="259">It is at once the ingenuity and the irony of Ziyah Gafić’s photographs that they contain these invisible territorial boundaries—like Bosnia today, you can’t necessarily see the lines of partition in Gafić’s images until you pry into them a bit. One photo, from 2013, shows an imam in a long black robe standing meditatively against a wash of concrete in an empty depot, awaiting the arrival of coffins that contain newly discovered remains of victims from the 1995 <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/the-legacy-of-the-srebrenica-massacre-twenty-years-later">genocide in Srebrenica</a>. The image is deeply sorrowful, but it becomes even more chilling if you know that Srebrenica was largely “ethnically cleansed” of its Bosniak population, and today lies in the middle of the almost entirely Serb Republika Srpska. Bosniak residents who have chosen to return to the area face steep difficulties, from finding employment to seeing that their children are properly educated in schools that often seek to instill a one-sided understanding of history. Another of Gafić’s photos, from 2014, shows a seemingly unremarkable sheath of gaunt pines curving up a mountain above the russet roofs of Sarajevo. If you look closely, you can see that some of the trunks have branches sprouting only on one side: these trees run along what was, in the nineties, one of the most contested frontlines on Mount Trebević, where Bosnian Serb forces held siege over Sarajevo from above; the branches on the other side of the trees were spliced off by artillery fire and never grew back. They stand today as a sort of fossilized imprint of the battle lines.</p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/3" data-total-words="520"/><p word_count="192" data-wc="192">“ ‘Dayton’ is at the same time one of the most celebrated and one of the most hated words in Bosnia,” Gafić told me. Celebrated, of course, because Dayton stopped the fighting and saved many lives. Yet it did so by giving in to the logic of the ethnic nationalism that had been used to incite violence, brokering a deal along ethnic lines that was intended as a peace agreement but has become, over two decades, a structure of governance. One Bosnian friend explained to me that Dayton had created such a weak foundation that the country couldn’t build anything on top of it; partly as a result, Bosnia today is very poor. She believed that there should have been another conference two or three years later to rectify what everyone knew was a problem from the outset. Gafić, who was born in Sarajevo in 1980, told me that he has been travelling around Bosnia to find out what the country looks like after “twenty years of the absence of war—not peace.” “Through sketches, I wanted to see where we are, if not as a nation then as a place,” he said.</p> <p word_count="185" data-wc="185">When I recently interviewed the Bosnian novelist Aleksandar Hemon, I told him about a jarring experience I’d had in <a href="http://harpers.org/archive/2015/12/the-counterparty/">Banja Luka</a>, the capital of Republika Srpska, when I travelled there on a reporting trip this summer. I had met a young, well-educated man about the same age as me—around thirty—who was a Serb. His view, which differed from most of the people I’d spent time with on my trip, was that ethnic identity would always be the most important factor in Bosnian politics, and that the idea of one cohesive country in the future was a fantasy. Hearing me recount this, Hemon told me that, unlike older Bosnians, who had spent half their lives as Yugoslavs, younger generations had had no such exposure to any larger political ideals. “Today it is impossible to establish in Bosnia a common utopian social project, as in, If we all work together this is what the society would be like,” Hemon said. Ethnic nationalists, he continued, “can only speak in terms of survival. There is no common societal project, and so there is no society.”</p> <p id="parallax9x2_frame" data-jivox-ad-id="constellation-parallax" data-constellation-id="parallax"/><a class="tny-page" name="/2" data-total-words="897"/><p word_count="88" data-wc="88">Still, it does a disservice to Gafić’s work to overlook the simple joy that emanates from many of his photos: two boys captured in midair as they cannonball into a lake in the middle of the mountains; a gutsy diving competition in the town of Konjic; a young girl snapping a selfie in Prijedor. These scenes of life carrying on, despite the recent history visited upon the country, convey a spirit of renewal, which draws some of its strength from the sublime beauty of the Bosnian landscape.</p> <p word_count="29" data-wc="29"><em>A selection of Ziyah Gafić’s photographs will be exhibited at the </em><a href="http://www.zemaljskimuzej.ba/"><em>National Museum of Bosnia and Herzegovina</em></a><em> as part of the twentieth anniversary of the Dayton Peace Agreement.</em></p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/4" data-total-words="1014"/><p word_count="19" data-wc="19"><i>Elisabeth Zerofsky’s work on this piece was supported by a grant from the Pulitzer Center on Crisis Reporting.</i></p> 						

					


 
					
					</div>
					</div>]]></description>		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/culture/photo-booth/boundaries-and-renewal-in-bosnia</link>			</item>

 	<item>		<title>Mali’s Hotel Hostage Siege</title>		<description><![CDATA[<div><div itemprop="articleBody" class="articleBody ad-container " id="articleBody">

												<figure class="horizontal attachment-large landscape img-expandable featured">
								<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Okeowo-Malis-Hotel-Hostage-Siege-1200.jpg" title="Mali’s Hotel Hostage Siege" itemprop="url">
									<img itemprop="image" src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Okeowo-Malis-Hotel-Hostage-Siege-290x150-1448061484.jpg" data-src-mobile="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Okeowo-Malis-Hotel-Hostage-Siege-290x150-1448061484.jpg" data-src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Okeowo-Malis-Hotel-Hostage-Siege-690x460-1448061241.jpg" class="post-load horizontal attachment-large" alt="The Radisson Blu is a popular spot for the local business and political élite, and also for travellers and expatriates—an immense amount of wealth and privilege concentrated in a seven-story hotel."/>								</a>

																<figcaption class="caption" itemprop="description">
									<span class="caption-text">The Radisson Blu is a popular spot for the local business and political élite, and also for travellers and expatriates—an immense amount of wealth and privilege concentrated in a seven-story hotel.</span>									<span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">
										<span class="hideFromView">Credit</span> Photograph by Joe Penney / Reuters / Landov									</span>								</figcaption>
															</figure>
							<a class="tny-slot" name="/2" data-total-words="0"/><a class="tny-page" name="/1" data-total-words="0"/><p class="descender" word_count="159" data-wc="159">The Radisson Blu hotel, in Bamako, Mali, is the city’s finest: peach-colored brick, with a swirling pool and sleek, minimalist rooms. As in other West African capitals, like Dakar and Lagos, the Radisson Blu is a popular spot for the local business and political élite, and also for travellers and expatriates—an immense amount of wealth and privilege concentrated in a seven-story hotel. So when <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/11/21/world/africa/mali-hotel-attack-radisson.html?hp&amp;action=click&amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;clickSource=story-heading&amp;module=a-lede-package-region&amp;region=top-news&amp;WT.nav=top-news">militants invaded the hotel</a>, earlier today, taking some hundred and seventy hostages, the meaning of their strike was clear. Al Mourabitoun, an Islamist group that has branded itself as Al Qaeda in West Africa and is based in the desert of northern Mali, claimed responsibility for the siege. As of now, the death toll is twenty-seven, including two terrorists. After most of the hostages escaped, the battle between Malian troops, assisted by French special forces, and the gunmen, who were holed up in the hotel’s top floors, went on for several hours.</p> <p word_count="187" data-wc="187">Mali’s struggles with Islamists reached a peak in 2012, when Islamist fighters <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/qaddafi-and-al-qaeda-whats-behind-the-coup-in-mali">occupied the north of the country</a> after a government coup. They were later driven out by a French-led military invasion, but elements lingered. In 2013, Al Mouribatoun emerged, and has since taken the blame for several attacks, including one on a hotel in Sevare, a town northeast of Bamako, where seventeen people, U.N. employees among them, were killed. One of the group’s leaders, a man named Mokhtar Belmokhtar, was behind an assault in 2013 on an Algerian gas plant, where thirty-seven hostages died. Though the Islamic State is believed to have worked alone in <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/topics/the-attacks-in-paris">attacking Paris</a> last week, Al Mouribatoun and others are likely inspired and influenced by the group. It’s reported that Al Qaeda in the Islamic Maghreb has long extended its funds, training, and arms to African extremist groups from Nigeria to Somalia. (In an audio recording, Al Mouribatoun said that a separate regional Al Qaeda affiliate also participated in the Radisson Blu raid.) Does sub-Saharan Africa now have to worry about the Islamic State strengthening these same homegrown terrorist groups, too?</p> <p word_count="198" data-wc="198">There are signs this may already be happening. The Global Terrorism Index, a study that ranks nations in terms of terrorist activity, was released this week, and showed that, last year, Boko Haram, the Islamist group originating in northeast Nigeria, caused more deaths than the Islamic State (6,644 deaths compared to 6,073). On Wednesday, a suicide bomber killed thirty-four people in the <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2015/nov/18/young-female-suicide-bombers-kill-15-in-nigeria-market-attack">northeastern city of Yola</a>. The next day, two young female suicide bombers killed at least fifteen people in a market in the northern metropolis of Kano. Authorities attributed all of these attacks to Boko Haram. Some Nigeria observers, myself included, have been reluctant to emphasize <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/a-kidnapped-family-and-terrorists-in-west-africa">Boko Haram</a>’s international ties over its specific domestic grievances. But in March, the group explicitly declared partnership with the Islamic State. This followed a winter in which its campaign became more grotesque and severe than ever, when the group <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-32435614">attempted</a> to govern towns under a thug-like Sharia rule, meting out harsh punishments. This year, the Nigerian Army was able to recover much of the territory it lost to Boko Haram. Even so, the group continues to pose a potent threat, in part because of its reënergizing by Iraq- and Syria-based counterparts.</p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/3" data-total-words="544"/><p word_count="97" data-wc="97">When attacks by Islamic State affiliates occur in African cities, towns, and villages, they are regarded by outsiders as far more mundane than similar events in Paris. It doesn’t spark surprise to hear of another Boko Haram suicide bombing or a skirmish in Mali, even as today’s hotel raid, exceptional for the way in which it targeted foreigners, garnered international attention. There should be a fear that, as these various terror campaigns intensify, no one outside of these countries will take much notice—until it’s impossible to reverse their growth and limit their reach.</p> <p word_count="72" data-wc="72">There are many details of the Bamako siege that still need to be parsed. Witnesses say they heard gunmen speaking in English. A few said they were freed after proving they could recite verses from the Koran. Others remember seeing up to ten terrorists, still others only two. And we don’t yet know much about the gunmen on the top of the Radisson Blu, fighting Malian soldiers until their last breaths.</p> 						

					


 
					
					</div>
					</div>]]></description>		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/malis-hotel-hostage-siege</link>			</item>

 	<item>		<title>Terror in Mali</title>		<description><![CDATA[<div><div itemprop="articleBody" class="articleBody ad-container " id="articleBody">

												<figure class="horizontal attachment-large landscape img-expandable featured">
								<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Anderson-Terror-in-Mali-1200.jpg" title="Terror in Mali" itemprop="url">
									<img itemprop="image" src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Anderson-Terror-in-Mali-290x150-1448052931.jpg" data-src-mobile="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Anderson-Terror-in-Mali-290x150-1448052931.jpg" data-src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Anderson-Terror-in-Mali-690x463-1448052806.jpg" class="post-load horizontal attachment-large" alt="After a hostage crisis today in Bamako, Mali, in which as many as twenty-seven people were killed, the country remains at risk."/>								</a>

																<figcaption class="caption" itemprop="description">
									<span class="caption-text">After a hostage crisis today in Bamako, Mali, in which as many as twenty-seven people were killed, the country remains at risk.</span>									<span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">
										<span class="hideFromView">Credit</span> Photograph by HABIBOU KOUYATE / AFP / Getty									</span>								</figcaption>
															</figure>
							<a class="tny-slot" name="/2" data-total-words="0"/><a class="tny-page" name="/1" data-total-words="0"/><p class="descender" word_count="172" data-wc="172">Today’s hostage crisis at the Radisson Blu Hotel, in the Malian capital of Bamako, where about a hundred people were held, has ended, with as many as twenty-seven deaths, according to a United Nations official. A joint operation by U.S. and Malian special forces ended the attack, which underscores the escalating pace of terrorist assaults by Islamist extremists. Coming so soon after the ISIS rampage in Paris, last Friday; the bombings in Beirut, a day earlier; and the downing of a Russian passenger plane over Egypt, on October 31st, this raid appears to have been an attempt by Al Mourabitoun, a largely Malian extremist group, to grab its own headlines. Most of these attacks have been on soft targets, where large numbers of civilians can be killed, and on secular Westerners, or infidels, in the eyes of the extremists. Others, of course, have targeted Muslims, such as last week’s Beirut bombings, which were intended to kill Shiites, who are vilified as apostates by the Sunni Muslim extremists of ISIS.</p> <p word_count="108" data-wc="108">The Bamako attack appears to be have been, if not anticipated, at least dealt with by the anti-terror forces now deployed throughout the region. In the past couple of years, Mali, Niger, and Chad have become bases for French and American special forces, which have quietly expanded their presence in the vulnerable Sahel region, in the wake of the disastrous revolution in Libya, in 2011, and the takeover, by Al Qaeda, of most of northern Mali for several months in 2012. (I <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2013/07/01/state-of-terror">wrote about the takeover</a> for the magazine in July, 2013.) The proximity of Boko Haram, the hyper-violent Islamist group, based in northeastern Nigeria, is another reason for the deployment.</p> <p word_count="144" data-wc="144">Despite the success of the eventual French campaign to oust Al Qaeda from the cities it occupied, including Timbuktu and Gao, it has been clear for some time that Mali’s troubles are not over. Because of its unique geography, the country has always been a strategic crossroads between Muslim North Africa and the predominately Christian countries of West Africa. That position, which has given it an extraordinarily rich cultural heritage, has also made it critical to the widening African battle against Islamists. In the face of the French assault, many of the terrorists fled unharmed to remote redoubts in the north, where Tuareg separatists gave them sanctuary. From these bases, and with access to the unmarked frontiers of Algeria and Libya, Islamists have fought back against the French and their Malian and Chadian allies in an inconclusive and obscure desert war ever since.</p> <p word_count="94" data-wc="94">Even before today’s attack, Islamist rebels from the north had demonstrated their ability to launch attacks in the south. In August, they seized the Byblos Hotel in the town of Sévaré, which is used by U.N. workers, and killed about a dozen people; previously, five were killed in an attack on a bar in Bamako, in March. What is clear is that terror groups, from Al Mourabitoun to ISIS, have grown increasingly effective. Despite American and Malian forces’ success in freeing the majority of today’s hostages, Mali remains at risk.</p> 						

					


 
					
					</div>
					</div>]]></description>		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/terror-in-mali</link>			</item>

 	<item>		<title>These So-Called Bad Movies Prove the Urgency of Film Criticism</title>		<description><![CDATA[<div><div itemprop="articleBody" class="articleBody ad-container " id="articleBody">

												<figure class="horizontal attachment-large landscape img-expandable featured">
								<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Brody-Urgency-of-Movie-Criticism-1200.jpg" title="These So-Called Bad Movies Prove the Urgency of Film Criticism" itemprop="url">
									<img itemprop="image" src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Brody-Urgency-of-Movie-Criticism-290x150-1448053707.jpg" data-src-mobile="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Brody-Urgency-of-Movie-Criticism-290x150-1448053707.jpg" data-src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Brody-Urgency-of-Movie-Criticism-690.jpg" class="post-load horizontal attachment-large" alt="Dustin Hoffman and Warren Beatty in Elaine May’s “Ishtar,” from 1987."/>								</a>

																<figcaption class="caption" itemprop="description">
									<span class="caption-text">Dustin Hoffman and Warren Beatty in Elaine May’s “Ishtar,” from 1987.</span>									<span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">
										<span class="hideFromView">Credit</span> Columbia Pictures / Everett 									</span>								</figcaption>
															</figure>
							<a class="tny-slot" name="/2" data-total-words="0"/><a class="tny-page" name="/1" data-total-words="0"/><p class="descender" word_count="92" data-wc="92">One of the great last lines in movie history is from the 1947 film noir “Nightmare Alley,” when two supporting characters catch a glimpse of the fallen hero: “How can a guy get so low?” “He reached too high.” That’s the story of one of the year’s best repertory series, “<a href="http://www.bam.org/film/2015/turkeys-for-thanksgiving">Turkeys for Thanksgiving</a>,” playing at <small>BAM</small> today through November 29th, which showcases films of great ambition that have ended up among the most reviled in the history of cinema largely because of those vast ambitions, which critics took pleasure in deriding.</p> <p word_count="132" data-wc="132">Many of these films are not only the markers of their directors’ ambitions, however—they fulfill those ambitions gloriously. They were often realized under difficult circumstances that reflected the challenges of filmmaking and the enduring conflict between the art and the business of movies. For many of these filmmakers, the effect on their careers—on their lives—of the release of these great, grand, and original films was disastrous. And perhaps the most destructive part of the experience is that, rather than experiencing the <em>succès d’estime</em> of connoisseurs’ acclaim despite commercial failure, these filmmakers endured devastating reviews from critics who insulted not only the films but their makers. (Some of those hostilities were aimed, in these pages, by Pauline Kael, notably at Michael Cimino, the director of “Heaven’s Gate.”)</p> <p word_count="85" data-wc="85">What most of these films have in common is an art of stylization. They were repudiated by critics who voiced the expectation that movies deliver life—or, rather, an imitation of life which they swallow as the real thing—through the behavior of characters rather than from the ensemble of elements in the movie over all. The craving for “characters” is a mark of collective solitude and a prime reason for the success of so-called quality television, which is mainly old-fashioned movie-making in modern garb.</p> <p word_count="148" data-wc="148">The greatest works on the list—“<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/movie-of-the-week-ishtar">Ishtar</a>,” “<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/dvd-of-the-week-monsieur-verdoux">Monsieur Verdoux</a>,” “<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/the-case-for-cleopatra">Cleopatra</a>,” “<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/the-modernity-of-heavens-gate">Heaven’s Gate</a>,” and “<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/movie-of-the-week-one-from-the-heart">One from the Heart</a>,” with “At Long Last Love” and “Dune” close behind—are masterworks of majestic, defiant, audacious artifice, in which the artifice is the very subject. With “<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/ishtar-and-the-film-maudit">Ishtar</a>,” that’s no surprise: after all, the title is the name of the fictitious country where the action is set, it’s a musical comedy, and it features Warren Beatty as a sex-starved nerd. With “<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/would-the-internet-have-rescued-heavens-gate">Heaven’s Gate</a>,” it’s a big surprise: the movie is a Western that depicts, in intimate and grandiose detail, bloody battles between big-time ranchers’ hired guns and the mainly immigrant owners of small farms. Kael, in her review, couldn’t reconcile Cimino’s style (which she admired) and the substance of the film, which she more or less didn’t acknowledge precisely because of the profusion of style.</p> <p word_count="144" data-wc="144">In “One from the Heart,” Francis Ford Coppola tips his hand about the trickery behind realism and the intimate cruelty on which a major production runs. Its story is the behind-the-scenes story of movie-making, the gory emotions behind the glorious spectacle. “<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/goings-on-about-town/movies/cleopatra">Cleopatra</a>” is one of the greatest works of historical drama ever filmed, and Joseph Mankiewicz recognizes how pageantry is inseparable from politics, how public image is inseparable from the war machine. With “At Long Last Love,” Peter Bogdanovich realizes flourishes of style approaching those of many classical filmmakers (such as Max Ophüls and Vincente Minnelli) while putting in the foreground a documentary recording of the intricate theatrical artifice on which this style depends. It’s an apt match with films from the same era by Jacques Rivette (such as “Céline and Julie Go Boating”) about the fusion of fantasy and identity.</p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/3" data-total-words="601"/><p word_count="103" data-wc="103">In “<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2013/04/15/comedy-terrors">Monsieur Verdoux</a>,” Charlie Chaplin definitively retires the Little Tramp (who, in “The Great Dictator,” was merely transmuted) to incarnate a little man who has become bigger than life—by means of death. His protagonist is a supreme aesthete risen from the <em>petite bourgeoisie</em> to cultivate an aristocratic taste for pleasure and murder and who, from the high perch of his ravenous refinement, satirically punches down at the narrow-minded masses manipulated into moralism by their self-interested overlords. (At the very least, when Chaplin’s movie suffered the brickbats of critics and the disdain of the public, they knew they were facing an opponent.)</p> <p word_count="101" data-wc="101">The codes of genres and the assumptions of categories are the packed-in sediment of presumptive critical expertise, the rigid learning that gets in the way of cinematic experience. Viewers tend to be more open to the holistic cinema—the power of images and gestures to evoke inner worlds—than critics. It isn’t that critics actually believe what they see, but that they fiercely desire to do so. There’s a longstanding tradition among critics of straining to affirm the importance and the social value of the art of movies in order to spare themselves the feeling of frivolity and hedonism.</p> <p id="parallax9x2_frame" data-jivox-ad-id="constellation-parallax" data-constellation-id="parallax"/><a class="tny-page" name="/2" data-total-words="805"/><p word_count="89" data-wc="89">That’s the other edge of the blade that has been stuck into the movies on the list: critical resentment of the artist’s prerogative. Most of these “turkeys” share a grand scale—they’re mighty works that took great efforts and great funds to realize, and that were victimized by advance reports about their directors’ out-of-control spending and willful behavior. Critics reviewed the budgets and the gossip rather than the movies, and the psychology of their repudiation is tied to a resentment of the ostensible arrogance of directors.</p> <p word_count="173" data-wc="173">When a studio invests large sums of money into movies of little artistic ambition, it’s the story of a business doing what businesses do. Critics often distinguished (with an often oblivious rigidity) between movies of artistic merit and purely commercial productions. (That’s why many of the greatest filmmakers of their time, such as Alfred Hitchcock, Howard Hawks, and Nicholas Ray, who all happened to work in Hollywood, went long unrecognized.) But, when a filmmaker hijacks the industrial machinery for a personal project, a critic’s aesthetic sense often goes out the window, and is replaced by umbrage, outrage, indignation. The attacks on Michael Cimino for “Heaven’s Gate,” on Elaine May for “Ishtar,” on Joseph Mankiewicz for “Cleopatra,” on Peter Bogdanovich for “At Long Last Love,” were spiked by resentment at filmmakers who managed to take over the system to realize their genius. It’s the instinctive conservatism of writers who, even without realizing it, became invested in the interests of the industry rather than in the well-being of the art.</p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/4" data-total-words="1067"/><p word_count="170" data-wc="170">Criticism is better than ever today, because critics tend to know more—and even know that there’s a lot we don’t know, because other critics are around to remind us. It’s a grim paradox. Just at the moment when the economics of working as a film critic are worse than ever, the practice is at a peak. Many of the best writers about movies are writing mainly online; many don’t have a regular outlet for their work; many aren’t read widely by moviegoers. But through the welcome amplification of social media, they’re read by other critics, and the influence of these mainly (but not exclusively) younger critics, ones who keep up with independent filmmaking and international cinema, who have deep and broad affinities for the history of cinema (which, thanks to home video and streaming, is more readily and diversely available than ever), makes itself felt in criticism at large. (The very programming of this series at <small>BAM</small> is a sign of their influence.)</p> <p word_count="87" data-wc="87">Yet the example provided by the air-quote turkeys of yesteryear gives me pause. The critical damnations and dismissals of earlier masterworks loom large as a fear today, a fear that great films are now being disdained—or, perhaps even worse, being simply ignored. Criticism is better than ever, but this only increases the sense of responsibility of the individual critic. By reminding us of great movies that might pass unnoticed or unrecognized, our colleagues remind us of the privilege of criticism as well as of its urgency.</p> <aside class="footer-content"><p><strong>Watch:</strong> Richard Brody on Elaine May’s “Ishtar,” from 1987.</p>
<p class="media-cne"/>
</aside>						

					


 
					
					</div>
					</div>]]></description>		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/these-so-called-bad-movies-prove-the-urgency-of-film-criticism</link>			</item>

 	<item>		<title>Our Betrayal of Syrian and Iraqi Refugees</title>		<description><![CDATA[<div><div itemprop="articleBody" class="articleBody ad-container " id="articleBody">

												<figure class="horizontal attachment-large landscape img-expandable featured">
								<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Packer-Our-Betrayal-of-Syrian-and-Iraqi-Refugees-1200.jpg" title="Our Betrayal of Syrian and Iraqi Refugees" itemprop="url">
									<img itemprop="image" src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Packer-Our-Betrayal-of-Syrian-and-Iraqi-Refugees-290-150.jpg" data-src-mobile="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Packer-Our-Betrayal-of-Syrian-and-Iraqi-Refugees-290-150.jpg" data-src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Packer-Our-Betrayal-of-Syrian-and-Iraqi-Refugees-690.jpg" class="post-load horizontal attachment-large" alt="House Speaker Paul Ryan speaks about the Syrian refugee crisis at a news briefing. The House recently passed a bill tightening the screening of potential refugees."/>								</a>

																<figcaption class="caption" itemprop="description">
									<span class="caption-text">House Speaker Paul Ryan speaks about the Syrian refugee crisis at a news briefing. The House recently passed a bill tightening the screening of potential refugees.</span>									<span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">
										<span class="hideFromView">Credit</span> Photograph by Jacquelyn Martin / AP									</span>								</figcaption>
															</figure>
							<a class="tny-slot" name="/2" data-total-words="0"/><a class="tny-page" name="/1" data-total-words="0"/><p class="descender" word_count="199" data-wc="199">This week, David Bowers, the Democratic mayor of Roanoke, Virginia, invoked the internment of Japanese-Americans during the Second World War as justification for keeping out Iraqi and Syrian refugees. I wonder if the mayor (who later apologized to anyone he might have offended) would have paused for one second in his headlong rush to join the <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/john-cassidy/donald-trump-and-americas-muslims">anti-refugee hysteria</a> sweeping America if he’d known that, among the residents of his city, there’s an Iraqi named Hayder. In 2003, Hayder was working as an interpreter for the 82nd Airborne Division, in Baghdad, when his convoy was ambushed by insurgents. Dragging an American sergeant out of the line of fire, Hayder was hit in both legs and nearly killed. He lost most of his right leg. Unable to work and in danger for his life, he fled Iraq with his wife and son to Jordan, where the family languished for years in deepening misery while getting nowhere in their efforts to get visas to the United States. Finally, in 2007, his case came to the attention of <a href="http://kirkwjohnson.com/">Kirk Johnson</a>, an American refugee advocate, and the next year Hayder and his family were resettled in Roanoke. In 2013, he became a U.S. citizen.</p> <p word_count="297" data-wc="297">Mayor Bowers hasn’t tried to have the family interned, not yet anyway, though the logic of his statement could have led him there—for keeping Muslim refugees out doesn’t solve the problem of the ones already here. (Donald Trump, tossing out answers that move beyond U.S. history to that of Nazi Germany, is talking about imposing mandatory registration on all Muslims in this country.) A bill that overwhelmingly passed the House on Thursday, by a vote of 289–137, with the support of fifty Democrats, would require the director of the F.B.I., the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the director of National Intelligence all to certify that each refugee applicant from Iraq or Syria poses no threat to the United States before being admitted. According to Betsy Fisher of the <a href="http://refugeerights.org/">International Refugee Assistance Project</a>, this group includes fifty-eight thousand Iraqis who have applied for resettlement through a program known as Direct Access, which was created by Congress for Iraqis who can show that they worked with the United States government or with American companies, non-profits, or media outlets. If it had the chance, the Islamic State would slaughter every one of them. The same goes for the many Yazidis applying for resettlement from Iraq—members of a religious minority who have been rounded up, enslaved, and murdered by ISIS. It’s already very, very hard for people like them to get here. <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2015/11/09/powerful-gestures">Iraqis and Syrians</a> are probably the most heavily vetted refugees in the history of the world. If three top government officials are going to be required to put their names and reputations on every admission, the very, very hard will become just about impossible. The House is counting on political cowardice and bureaucratic indifference to advance the cause of irrationality and bigotry.</p> <p word_count="128" data-wc="128">We’ve seen this kind of frenzied meanness during past crises, real or perceived. It hit the country in the form of the Palmer raids after the First World War, with the internment camps during the Second World War (Franklin Roosevelt’s most shameful act), and in the McCarthyite politics of the nineteen-fifties. Such moments were made for Ted Cruz—this generation’s Joe McCarthy. Not to be outdone by the House, on Thursday he introduced a bill in the Senate called the Terrorist Refugee Infiltration Prevention Act. It would add refugees from Libya, Yemen, and Somalia to the Syrians and Iraqis on what is effectively a black list. (There was no explanation for the absence of Afghanistan, Mali, and Nigeria as potential sources of Terrorist Refugee Infiltration.)</p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/3" data-total-words="624"/><p word_count="170" data-wc="170">Cruz’s bill would allow two exceptions to the barred door. One is for individuals who have provided “substantial assistance” to the U.S.—though the bill would require certification from the leaders of four government agencies that it was “a level of assistance without which the United States could not achieve the purposes for which the assistance was provided or sought.” This tortured language raises the already-high barrier and would keep out pretty much every last Iraqi, of any faith, who lost his leg or his safety or his future while helping Americans in his country. The second exception, Cruz explained, is for “Christians, Yazidis, small minorities that are facing genocide.” This is a back-door way of legislating a religious test for refugees, by exploiting a powerful word that didn’t seem to move Cruz when it mattered. Last year, after Yazidis were rounded up, executed, and enslaved by the Islamic State, Cruz voted against a bill that gave President Barack Obama authority and funds to fight the organization.</p> <p word_count="63" data-wc="63">President Obama has been admirable in refusing to give in to this stampede. He warned unnamed politicians “not to feed that dark impulse inside of us.” Obama has a lousy track record of actually admitting Iraqi and Syrian refugees, but at least he doesn’t exclude any on the basis of religion, or try to justify his poor performance by betraying liberal values.</p> <p id="parallax9x2_frame" data-jivox-ad-id="constellation-parallax" data-constellation-id="parallax"/><a class="tny-page" name="/2" data-total-words="857"/><p word_count="186" data-wc="186">A lot of people in this country are disgracing themselves this week. They include politicians of both parties—though many more Republicans than Democrats—and all regions. Their motives vary: deep-seated bigotry, unreasoning fear, spinelessness, opportunism, or some unholy mix of them all. During the House hearings, Republicans kept demanding guarantees of absolute security. “I haven’t heard a single one of you say there’s no risk,” Representative Trey Gowdy, Republican of South Carolina and chairman of the Judiciary Committee, told Administration witnesses. There’s no such thing as no risk. Parisians could stop going out to cafés, Germans could turn back every single Syrian at the border, Americans could stop admitting anyone as a refugee, and there would still be risks. It’s absurd, and infantilizing, to demand that our officials promise to keep us absolutely safe. We don’t live that way, nor should we. Instead, we have to find the balance between safety and a decent life in a free society during an age of terror. Like every compromise, it will leave us unsatisfied. But the alternative is unfreedom and injustice.</p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/4" data-total-words="1043"/><p word_count="224" data-wc="224">On Thursday night, as the House was passing its anti-refugee bill, I moderated a panel at New York University with four women who were visiting from Syria. I wish Ted Cruz, Trey Gowdy, and other panic-stricken demagogues had been in the audience. One of the Syrians, a journalist named <a href="http://ijnet.org/en/blog/qa-zaina-erhaim-teaching-citizen-journalists-survive-syria">Zaina Erhaim</a>, screened four short films she’s made about women going about their lives in Aleppo, Syria, which is one of the least safe places in the world. Two of her subjects were on the panel—Ahed and Zein. They both work for international relief agencies in Aleppo, distributing bread and bandaging the wounded. Zein also teaches small children in a school that is literally underground. A fourth woman, <a href="http://syrianobserver.com/EN/Features/29856/My_Mother_The_Accidental_Activist">Rafea</a>, works as an activist and writer in Damascus. All four are from Sunni Muslim families, though Rafea is a self-described atheist; Ahed and Zein wore the hijab. To get to New York, Ahed had to spend several nights in the mountains outside Aleppo, since the Turkish border crossing is closed and the roads aren’t safe. Asked what she wants from Americans, Erhaim, the filmmaker, said an end to air attacks on cities, and a safe zone for civilians along the border. All of the women said that they no longer have any hope for Syria, but all of them are going back there.</p> <p word_count="91" data-wc="91">Caught between the Assad regime, the Islamic State, and an indifferent world, these women still feel and think, they scoff at the beliefs of the extremists, rage at the cruelty of Assad, cry while they stitch up children, mourn the dead, tease and comfort one another. They’ve found depths of kindness and resilience, hatred and love, that they didn’t know before the war. The Syrian horror hasn’t killed their humanity—if anything, it’s intensified. I went home, in the rain, with a sense of wonder and shame.</p> 						

					


 
					
					</div>
					</div>]]></description>		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/our-betrayal-of-syrian-and-iraqi-refugees</link>			</item>

 	<item>		<title>Textbooks for Peace in Israel and the West Bank</title>		<description><![CDATA[<div><div itemprop="articleBody" class="articleBody ad-container " id="articleBody">

												<figure class="horizontal attachment-large landscape featured">
								<a href="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Shipler-A-Problem-of-Education-in-Israel-and-West-Bank1-690.jpg" title="Textbooks for Peace in Israel and the West Bank" itemprop="url">
									<img itemprop="image" src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Shipler-A-Problem-of-Education-in-Israel-and-West-Bank1-290x150-1448049665.jpg" data-src-mobile="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Shipler-A-Problem-of-Education-in-Israel-and-West-Bank1-290x150-1448049665.jpg" data-src="http://www.newyorker.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Shipler-A-Problem-of-Education-in-Israel-and-West-Bank1-690.jpg" class="post-load horizontal attachment-large" alt="Among Palestinian and Israeli teen-agers, education has grown into an unavoidable obstacle to co-existence."/>								</a>

																<figcaption class="caption" itemprop="description">
									<span class="caption-text">Among Palestinian and Israeli teen-agers, education has grown into an unavoidable obstacle to co-existence.</span>									<span class="credit" itemprop="copyrightHolder">
										<span class="hideFromView">Credit</span> Photograph by Patrick Zachmann / Magnum									</span>								</figcaption>
															</figure>
							<a class="tny-slot" name="/2" data-total-words="0"/><a class="tny-page" name="/1" data-total-words="0"/><p class="descender" word_count="83" data-wc="83">A small, sad record was set on Thursday, for the largest number of deaths in a single day in the two-month rash of scattered attacks by Palestinians in Israel and the West Bank. Five people died, two by stabbing in Tel Aviv and three by automatic gunfire near Alon Shvut, a Jewish settlement. In the shadow of the attacks in Paris, however, this everyday violence has slipped nearly out of sight. It has become so routine that it remains in our peripheral vision.</p> <p word_count="71" data-wc="71">No peace talks are scheduled, and even if they were they would need to reach more deeply into ordinary beliefs than negotiators can usually manage. Those beliefs are shaped in schools, which fail to teach children to think sympathetically about the other’s past and recent history. As touchy-feely as this might seem, education has grown into an unavoidable obstacle to co-existence, for it misinforms perceptions across the lines of conflict.</p> <p word_count="48" data-wc="48">In the past two decades, I have met with Palestinian and Israeli teen-agers, on visits to high schools in the West Bank and Israel. To take some measure of the problem, I have posed a question to them, as a litmus test. “Who are the victims?” I ask.</p> <p word_count="47" data-wc="47">“We are,” is the most common response, given with brisk certainty by young people who cannot award the dignity of victimhood to those across the barricades. In striking symmetry, each group stakes a claim to unique suffering, which is lodged in distortions and silences about the past.</p> <p word_count="60" data-wc="60">So I listen for the answer that an Israeli girl offered at a school in Jerusalem, in 1993. When her classmates said, “We are,” she countered that Palestinians were victims as well. The next day, at a Palestinian school in Ramallah, another girl said the same: “There are victims on both sides.” The two held their lonely dissents against their peers.</p> <p word_count="103" data-wc="103">That was shortly after the Oslo accords were signed, a time when peace seemed possible. Eight years later, even as the second intifada was boiling into violence, seniors at the same schools voiced more empathy. All but one in a group of seven Jewish students, and about half of the Palestinians, acknowledged that there were victims on both sides. Then a backslide occurred, until, by November, 2014, amid scattered attacks on Israelis in Jerusalem, a group of Jewish students was divided: four called Jews the only victims, and three said “everybody.” The seven Palestinians at the Ramallah school were unanimous: the victims were “us.”</p> <p word_count="101" data-wc="101">These are small, unscientific samples. But they are vignettes of larger attitudes, which grow out of the failures of education and leadership to help Israelis and Palestinians come to see each other’s experience. Borders may be negotiated, territory may be swapped, security measures may be codified. But the harder issues are steeped in history. If each side fails to respect the other’s story, it is difficult to imagine how Jerusalem can be shared, and compromise will be elusive on the right of return—by Jews to biblical lands on the West Bank, by Palestinians to lost villages inside Israel.</p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/3" data-total-words="513"/><p word_count="149" data-wc="149">If you do not know about the Holocaust, for example, you cannot comprehend the spectre of vulnerability that haunts and toughens Israel. Yet the Holocaust is largely absent from the Palestinian Authority’s textbooks, according to Sami Adwan, of Bethlehem University, who is the leading Palestinian researcher on a <a href="http://articles.latimes.com/2013/feb/04/world/la-fg-wn-israeli-palestinian-textbooks-unbalanced-20130204">2013 study</a> of the textbooks used in Israel and the West Bank, which was initiated by the Council of Religious Institutions of the Holy Land, and funded by the State Department. The omission allows the Jews who migrated to Palestine from Europe to be portrayed not with compassion, as refugees, but with resentment, as tools of colonialism. One of the few Palestinians who has tried to teach the Holocaust, Muhammad S. Dajani Daoudi, included it in a course at Al Quds University, in Jerusalem, and took twenty-seven Palestinian students to <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/04/21/world/middleeast/palestinian-teaches-tolerance-via-holocaust.html">visit Auschwitz</a> last year. He was vilified and <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2014/08/a-plea-for-empathy-in-the-middle-east/375990/">hounded into resigning</a>.</p> <p word_count="61" data-wc="61">In the silence about the Nazi genocide, imaginary tales reverberate. Jews came from Europe, a student at a Palestinian girls’ school told me, because “they were causing lots of problems in these European countries.” I thought I had misheard. The Jews were having problems? I asked. “No, the Jews were causing problems,” she repeated. “So they wanted to get them out.”</p> <p word_count="73" data-wc="73">What problems? The girls summoned classic anti-Semitism. They were traders with “lots of money,” one said. How about the Holocaust? “Hitler burned half of them,” she conceded, but another student added: “They were trying to take over there. They were trying to take control. They wanted to take anything they could using power. These countries wanted to get them out and found Palestine was the place they wanted to kick them out to.”</p> <p word_count="70" data-wc="70">And why Palestine? Here was an opportunity for the sixteen- and seventeen-year-olds to acknowledge Jews’ ancient ties to this contested land. But they did not. One believed that Palestine was chosen “because it’s in a very strategic area.” Another said, “They figured that by coming here they would find the link that would tie them to this land, and therefore take over the land and make it their own.”</p> <p id="parallax9x2_frame" data-jivox-ad-id="constellation-parallax" data-constellation-id="parallax"/><a class="tny-page" name="/2" data-total-words="866"/><p word_count="71" data-wc="71">All eight students firmly denied that Jewish temples had ever stood in Jerusalem, a repudiation that has gained widespread currency among Palestinians, both Christian and Muslim. Textbooks don’t have to go that far; merely ignoring Jewish history in Jerusalem creates a vacuum, into which flow fabrications. This one is a way of saying: you don’t belong, you never belonged, your presence is an aberration that must eventually be rectified.</p> <p word_count="68" data-wc="68">By contrast, Israeli textbooks acknowledge Islam’s connection to Jerusalem, according to Daniel Bar-Tal, of Tel Aviv University, the leading Israeli researcher for the Council of Religious Institutions study. Their central silence concerns the Palestinians’ angry pain over the founding of the Jewish state, which they mourn as “Al Nakba” (“the catastrophe”), in which they see alien outsiders as having stolen their land, killing and expelling innocent Arabs.</p> <a class="tny-slot" name="/4" data-total-words="1005"/><p word_count="87" data-wc="87">This narrative must be heard, according to the former Israeli education minister Shai Piron, because it is embraced not just by Palestinian refugees abroad but also by a fifth of Israel’s citizens—Arabs who remained there and their descendants. “I’m for teaching the Nakba to all students in Israel,” Piron declared last March. “I do not think that a student can go through the Israeli educational system, while twenty per cent of students have an ethos, a story, and he does not know that story.”</p> <p word_count="66" data-wc="66">Israel’s private ultra-Orthodox schools teach little about the Palestinian experience, the study concluded. In their textbooks, Israel’s 1948 war of independence is purely heroic and morally flawless, waged after Arab countries rejected the U.N. proposal to partition the territory into Jewish and Arab states. Unmentioned are the expulsions of Arabs from some villages by Israeli forces, as documented by Israeli historians from official archives.</p> <p word_count="106" data-wc="106">References to the expulsions have crept into textbooks for the two state-run systems—secular and religious schools—but they lack the human stories that might increase Jewish students’ emotional grasp of Palestinians’ grievances. Israeli high-school students in one history class found the official texts so confining that they asked the teacher for the Palestinian perspective, which she told me she provided from documents online. But, despite these eddies of interest in the other’s interpretations of the past, most children are not taught to recognize the competing truths woven into the Jewish and the Palestinian historical narratives. And the echoes of childhood last for a generation.</p> 						

					


 
					
					</div>
					</div>]]></description>		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/a-problem-of-education-in-israel-and-the-west-bank</link>			</item>

 </channel>

 </rss>
